<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cvrfdoc xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.icasi.org/CVRF/schema/cvrf/1.1">
  <DocumentTitle>Cisco Intrusion Prevention System MainApp Secure Socket Layer Denial of Service Vulnerability</DocumentTitle>
  <DocumentType>Cisco Security Advisory</DocumentType>
  <DocumentPublisher Type="Vendor">
    <ContactDetails>Emergency Support:
+1 877 228 7302 (toll-free within North America)
+1 408 525 6532 (International direct-dial)
Non-emergency Support:
Email: psirt@cisco.com
Support requests that are received via e-mail are typically acknowledged within 48 hours.</ContactDetails>
    <IssuingAuthority>Cisco product security incident response is the responsibility of the Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT). The Cisco PSIRT is a dedicated, global team that manages the receipt, investigation, and public reporting of security vulnerability information that is related to Cisco products and networks. The on-call Cisco PSIRT works 24x7 with Cisco customers, independent security researchers, consultants, industry organizations, and other vendors to identify possible security issues with Cisco products and networks.
More information can be found in Cisco Security Vulnerability Policy available at http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html</IssuingAuthority>
  </DocumentPublisher>
  <DocumentTracking>
    <Identification>
      <ID>cisco-sa-20150311-ips</ID>
    </Identification>
    <Status>Final</Status>
    <Version>1.0</Version>
    <RevisionHistory>
      <Revision>
        <Number>1.0</Number>
        <Date>2015-03-11T14:48:35</Date>
        <Description>Initial public release.</Description>
      </Revision>
    </RevisionHistory>
    <InitialReleaseDate>2015-03-11T16:00:00</InitialReleaseDate>
    <CurrentReleaseDate>2015-03-11T14:48:35</CurrentReleaseDate>
    <Generator>
      <Engine>TVCE</Engine>
    </Generator>
  </DocumentTracking>
  <DocumentNotes>
    <Note Title="Summary" Type="General" Ordinal="1">The Cisco
Intrusion Prevention System (IPS) Software has a vulnerability within the SSL/TLS subsystem utilized by the web management interface which could allow an
unauthenticated, remote attacker to cause a denial of service (DoS)
condition.



Cisco has released software updates that address this vulnerability. This advisory is available at the following link:

http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20150311-ips["http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20150311-ips"]</Note>
  </DocumentNotes>
  <DocumentReferences>
    <Reference Type="Self">
      <URL>http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20150311-ips</URL>
      <Description>Cisco Intrusion Prevention System MainApp Secure Socket Layer Denial of Service Vulnerability</Description>
    </Reference>
    <Reference>
      <URL>http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/viewAlert.x?alertId=37708</URL>
      <Description>Cisco Intrusion Prevention System MainApp Secure Socket Layer Denial of Service Vulnerability</Description>
    </Reference>
    <Reference>
      <URL>http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/viewAlert.x?alertId=37708</URL>
      <Description>Cisco Intrusion Prevention System MainApp Secure Socket Layer Denial of Service Vulnerability</Description>
    </Reference>
  </DocumentReferences>
  <ProductTree xmlns="http://www.icasi.org/CVRF/schema/prod/1.1">
    <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-197620">Cisco Intrusion Prevention System (IPS) 7.2(1)E4</FullProductName>
  </ProductTree>
  <Vulnerability Ordinal="1" xmlns="http://www.icasi.org/CVRF/schema/vuln/1.1">
    <Title>Cisco Intrusion Prevention System MainApp Secure Socket Layer Denial of Service Vulnerability</Title>
    <ID SystemName="Cisco Bug ID">CSCuq40652</ID>
    <Notes>
      <Note Title="Summary" Type="Summary" Ordinal="1">A vulnerability within the SSL/TLS subsystem utilized by the web management interface
of Cisco Intrusion Prevention System (IPS) Software could allow an
unauthenticated, remote attacker to cause a denial of service (DoS)
condition.



The vulnerability is due to a potential race condition when handling multiple HTTPS requests on the management interface. An attacker could exploit this
vulnerability by negotiating a number of HTTPS connections with the management interface. An exploit could allow the attacker to make the MainApp process unresponsive. This creates a DoS condition because the Cisco IPS sensor is not able to execute several critical tasks including alert notification, event store management, and sensor authentication. The Cisco IPS web server is also unavailable while the MainApp process is unresponsive. 



Additionally, due to this general system failure, other processes such as the Analysis Engine may not work properly. The Cisco IPS may not continue to process traffic because the Analysis Engine process may not work properly. If the Cisco IPS is configured in promiscuous mode, mitigation actions that require MainApp processing such as the request-block-host or request-rate-limit event-actions may be unavailable. If the Cisco IPS is configured in inline mode, the sensor may not correctly perform inspection and mitigation actions, and may drop packets transiting the affected device. The condition persists until the device has been restarted.



The vulnerability can be triggered only by SSL/TLS traffic directed to the TCP port and IP address of the management interface associated with the web server. The default TCP port is 443. Packets transiting an affected device through the sensing interfaces cannot be used to trigger this vulnerability.</Note>
      <Note Title="Cisco Bug IDs" Type="Other" Ordinal="3">CSCuq40652</Note>
    </Notes>
    <CVE>CVE-2015-0654</CVE>
    <ProductStatuses>
      <Status Type="Known Affected">
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-197620</ProductID>
      </Status>
    </ProductStatuses>
    <CVSSScoreSets>
      <ScoreSet>
        <BaseScore>7.1</BaseScore>
        <TemporalScore>5.9</TemporalScore>
        <Vector>AV:N/AC:M/Au:N/C:N/I:N/A:C/E:F/RL:OF/RC:C</Vector>
      </ScoreSet>
    </CVSSScoreSets>
    <Remediations>
      <Remediation Type="Workaround">
        <Description>There is no workaround for this vulnerability.
</Description>
      </Remediation>
    </Remediations>
    <References>
      <Reference Type="Self">
        <URL>http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20150311-ips</URL>
        <Description>Cisco Intrusion Prevention System MainApp Secure Socket Layer Denial of Service Vulnerability</Description>
      </Reference>
    </References>
  </Vulnerability>
</cvrfdoc>