<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cvrfdoc xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/cvrf">
  <DocumentTitle>Cisco IOS XE Software Web UI Remote Access Privilege Escalation Vulnerability</DocumentTitle>
  <DocumentType>Cisco Security Advisory</DocumentType>
  <DocumentPublisher Type="Vendor">
    <ContactDetails>Emergency Support:
+1 877 228 7302 (toll-free within North America)
+1 408 525 6532 (International direct-dial)
Non-emergency Support:
Email: psirt@cisco.com
Support requests that are received via e-mail are typically acknowledged within 48 hours.</ContactDetails>
    <IssuingAuthority>Cisco product security incident response is the responsibility of the Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT). The Cisco PSIRT is a dedicated, global team that manages the receipt, investigation, and public reporting of security vulnerability information that is related to Cisco products and networks. The on-call Cisco PSIRT works 24x7 with Cisco customers, independent security researchers, consultants, industry organizations, and other vendors to identify possible security issues with Cisco products and networks.
More information can be found in Cisco Security Vulnerability Policy available at http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html</IssuingAuthority>
  </DocumentPublisher>
  <DocumentTracking>
    <Identification>
      <ID>cisco-sa-20180328-xepriv</ID>
    </Identification>
    <Status>Final</Status>
    <Version>1.0</Version>
    <RevisionHistory>
      <Revision>
        <Number>1.0</Number>
        <Date>2018-03-28T15:03:55</Date>
        <Description>Initial public release.</Description>
      </Revision>
    </RevisionHistory>
    <InitialReleaseDate>2018-03-28T16:00:00</InitialReleaseDate>
    <CurrentReleaseDate>2018-03-28T15:03:55</CurrentReleaseDate>
    <Generator>
      <Engine>TVCE</Engine>
    </Generator>
  </DocumentTracking>
  <DocumentNotes>
    <Note Title="Summary" Type="Summary" Ordinal="1">A vulnerability in the web-based user interface (web UI) of Cisco IOS XE Software could allow an authenticated, remote attacker to gain elevated privileges on an affected device.

The vulnerability exists because the affected software does not reset the privilege level for each web UI session. An attacker who has valid credentials for an affected device could exploit this vulnerability by remotely accessing a VTY line to the device. A successful exploit could allow the attacker to access an affected device with the privileges of the user who previously logged in to the web UI.

Cisco has released software updates that address this vulnerability. There are no workarounds that address this vulnerability.

This advisory is available at the following link:
https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20180328-xepriv ["https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20180328-xepriv"]
This advisory is part of the March 28, 2018, release of the Cisco IOS and IOS XE Software Security Advisory Bundled Publication, which includes 20 Cisco Security Advisories that describe 22 vulnerabilities. For a complete list of the advisories and links to them, see Cisco Event Response: March 2018 Semiannual Cisco IOS and IOS XE Software Security Advisory Bundled Publication ["https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/viewErp.x?alertId=ERP-66682"].</Note>
    <Note Title="Vulnerable Products" Type="General" Ordinal="2">This vulnerability affects Cisco devices that are running a vulnerable release of Cisco IOS XE Software, if the HTTP Server feature is enabled and authentication, authorization, and accounting (AAA) authorization is not configured for EXEC sessions. The default state of the HTTP Server feature is version-dependent.

This vulnerability was introduced in Cisco IOS XE Software Release 16.1.1. For more information about which Cisco IOS XE Software releases are vulnerable, see the Fixed Software ["#fixed"] section of this advisory.
  Assessing the HTTP Server Configuration
To determine whether the HTTP Server feature is enabled for a device, administrators can log in to the device and use the show running-config | include http (secure|server) command in the CLI to check for the presence of the ip http server command or the ip http secure-server command in the global configuration. If either command is present and configured, the HTTP Server feature is enabled for the device.

The following example shows the output of the show running-config | include http (secure|server) command for a router that has the HTTP Server feature enabled:


Router# show running-config | include http (secure|server)
  ip http server  ip http secure-server
    Assessing the AAA Configuration
To determine whether AAA authorization for EXEC sessions is configured for a device, administrators can log in to the device and use the show running-config | include aaa authorization exec command in the CLI to check for the presence of the aaa authorization exec [options] command in the global configuration.

The following example shows the output of the show running-config | include aaa authorization exec command for a router that is configured to have its AAA authorization enforced by a TACACS+ server and is therefore not affected by this vulnerability:


Router# show running-config | include aaa authorization exec
  aaa authorization exec use-tacacs group tacacs+
    Determining the Cisco IOS XE Software Release
To determine which Cisco IOS XE Software release is running on a device, administrators can log in to the device, use the show version command in the CLI, and then refer to the system banner that appears. If the device is running Cisco IOS XE Software, the system banner displays Cisco IOS Software, Cisco IOS XE Software, or similar text.

The following example shows the output of the command for a device that is running Cisco IOS XE Software Release 16.2.1 and has an installed image name of CAT3K_CAA-UNIVERSALK9-M:


ios-xe-device# show version
  Cisco IOS Software, Catalyst L3 Switch Software (CAT3K_CAA-UNIVERSALK9-M), Version Denali 16.2.1, RELEASE SOFTWARE (fc1)  Technical Support: http://www.cisco.com/techsupport  Copyright (c) 1986-2016 by Cisco Systems, Inc.  Compiled Sun 27-Mar-16 21:47 by mcpre  .  .  .

For information about the naming and numbering conventions for Cisco IOS XE Software releases, see the Cisco IOS and NX-OS Software Reference Guide ["https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/about/security-center/ios-nx-os-reference-guide.html"].</Note>
    <Note Title="Products Confirmed Not Vulnerable" Type="General" Ordinal="3">No other Cisco products are currently known to be affected by this vulnerability.

Cisco has confirmed that this vulnerability does not affect Cisco IOS Software, Cisco IOS XR Software, or Cisco NX-OS Software.</Note>
    <Note Title="Indicators of Compromise" Type="General" Ordinal="4">Administrators may identify exploitation of this vulnerability by using the AAA accounting logs for an affected system to identify users who are executing commands at a higher privilege level than their assigned privilege level.</Note>
    <Note Title="Workarounds" Type="General" Ordinal="5">There are no workarounds that address this vulnerability.

Administrators who do not require the web UI may mitigate this vulnerability by disabling the HTTP Server feature on an affected device. To disable the feature, use the no ip http server and no ip http secure-server commands in the CLI.

Administrators who require the web UI may mitigate this vulnerability by enabling AAA authorization for EXEC sessions, locally or via a AAA server, for an affected device.</Note>
    <Note Title="Fixed Software" Type="General" Ordinal="6">Cisco has released free software updates that address the vulnerability described in this advisory. Customers may only install and expect support for software versions and feature sets for which they have purchased a license. By installing, downloading, accessing, or otherwise using such software upgrades, customers agree to follow the terms of the Cisco software license:
https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/products/end-user-license-agreement.html ["https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/products/end-user-license-agreement.html"]

Additionally, customers may only download software for which they have a valid license, procured from Cisco directly, or through a Cisco authorized reseller or partner. In most cases this will be a maintenance upgrade to software that was previously purchased. Free security software updates do not entitle customers to a new software license, additional software feature sets, or major revision upgrades.

When considering software upgrades, customers are advised to regularly consult the advisories for Cisco products, which are available from the Cisco Security Advisories and Alerts page ["https://www.cisco.com/go/psirt"], to determine exposure and a complete upgrade solution.

In all cases, customers should ensure that the devices to be upgraded contain sufficient memory and confirm that current hardware and software configurations will continue to be supported properly by the new release. If the information is not clear, customers are advised to contact the Cisco Technical Assistance Center (TAC) or their contracted maintenance providers.

Customers Without Service Contracts

Customers who purchase directly from Cisco but do not hold a Cisco service contract and customers who make purchases through third-party vendors but are unsuccessful in obtaining fixed software through their point of sale should obtain upgrades by contacting the Cisco TAC:
https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/support/web/tsd-cisco-worldwide-contacts.html ["https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/support/web/tsd-cisco-worldwide-contacts.html"]

Customers should have the product serial number available and be prepared to provide the URL of this advisory as evidence of entitlement to a free upgrade.
                        Cisco IOS and IOS XE Software
To help customers determine their exposure to vulnerabilities in Cisco IOS and IOS XE Software, Cisco provides a tool, the Cisco IOS Software Checker ["https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/softwarechecker.x"], that identifies any Cisco Security Advisories that impact a specific software release and the earliest release that fixes the vulnerabilities described in each advisory (“First Fixed”). If applicable, the tool also returns the earliest release that fixes all the vulnerabilities described in all the advisories identified (“Combined First Fixed”).

Customers can use this tool to perform the following tasks:

Initiate a search by choosing one or more releases from a drop-down list or uploading a file from a local system for the tool to parse
Enter the output of the show version command for the tool to parse
Create a custom search by including all previously published Cisco Security Advisories, a specific advisory, or all advisories in the most recent bundled publication

To determine whether a release is affected by any published Cisco Security Advisory, use the Cisco IOS Software Checker ["https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/softwarechecker.x"] on Cisco.com or enter a Cisco IOS Software or Cisco IOS XE Software release—for example, 15.1(4)M2 or 3.13.8S—in the following field:</Note>
    <Note Title="Vulnerability Policy" Type="General" Ordinal="7">To learn about Cisco security vulnerability disclosure policies and publications, see the Security Vulnerability Policy ["http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html"]. This document also contains instructions for obtaining fixed software and receiving security vulnerability information from Cisco.</Note>
    <Note Title="Exploitation and Public Announcements" Type="General" Ordinal="8">The Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT) is not aware of any public announcements or malicious use of the vulnerability that is described in this advisory.</Note>
    <Note Title="Source" Type="General" Ordinal="9">This vulnerability was found during internal security testing.</Note>
    <Note Title="Legal Disclaimer" Type="Legal Disclaimer" Ordinal="10">THIS DOCUMENT IS PROVIDED ON AN "AS IS" BASIS AND DOES NOT IMPLY ANY KIND OF GUARANTEE OR WARRANTY, INCLUDING THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY OR FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR USE. YOUR USE OF THE INFORMATION ON THE DOCUMENT OR MATERIALS LINKED FROM THE DOCUMENT IS AT YOUR OWN RISK. CISCO RESERVES THE RIGHT TO CHANGE OR UPDATE THIS DOCUMENT AT ANY TIME.

A standalone copy or paraphrase of the text of this document that omits the distribution URL is an uncontrolled copy and may lack important information or contain factual errors. The information in this document is intended for end users of Cisco products.</Note>
  </DocumentNotes>
  <DocumentReferences>
    <Reference Type="Self">
      <URL>https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20180328-xepriv</URL>
      <Description>Cisco IOS XE Software Web UI Remote Access Privilege Escalation Vulnerability</Description>
    </Reference>
    <Reference>
      <URL>https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityBundle/cisco-sa-20180328-bundle</URL>
      <Description>Summary of the Semiannual Cisco IOS and IOS XE Software Security Advisory Bundled Publication, March 28, 2018	</Description>
    </Reference>
    <Reference>
      <URL>https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityBundle/cisco-sa-20180328-bundle</URL>
      <Description>Summary of the Semiannual Cisco IOS and IOS XE Software Security Advisory Bundled Publication, March 28, 2018	</Description>
    </Reference>
    <Reference>
      <URL>http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/viewErp.x?alertId=ERP-66682</URL>
      <Description>Cisco Event Response: March 2018 Semiannual Cisco IOS and IOS XE Software Security Advisory Bundled Publication</Description>
    </Reference>
    <Reference>
      <URL>http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/viewErp.x?alertId=ERP-66682</URL>
      <Description>Cisco Event Response: March 2018 Semiannual Cisco IOS and IOS XE Software Security Advisory Bundled Publication</Description>
    </Reference>
  </DocumentReferences>
  <ProductTree xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/prod">
    <Branch Name="Cisco" Type="Vendor">
      <Branch Name="Cisco IOS XE Software" Type="Product Name">
        <Branch Name="16.1" Type="Product Version">
          <Branch Name="16.1.1" Type="Service Pack">
            <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-212436">Cisco IOS XE Software 16.1 16.1.1</FullProductName>
          </Branch>
          <Branch Name="16.1.2" Type="Service Pack">
            <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-213100">Cisco IOS XE Software 16.1 16.1.2</FullProductName>
          </Branch>
          <Branch Name="16.1.3" Type="Service Pack">
            <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-214993">Cisco IOS XE Software 16.1 16.1.3</FullProductName>
          </Branch>
        </Branch>
        <Branch Name="16.2" Type="Product Version">
          <Branch Name="16.2.1" Type="Service Pack">
            <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-213809">Cisco IOS XE Software 16.2 16.2.1</FullProductName>
          </Branch>
          <Branch Name="16.2.2" Type="Service Pack">
            <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-217253">Cisco IOS XE Software 16.2 16.2.2</FullProductName>
          </Branch>
        </Branch>
        <Branch Name="16.3" Type="Product Version">
          <Branch Name="16.3.1" Type="Service Pack">
            <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-213960">Cisco IOS XE Software 16.3 16.3.1</FullProductName>
          </Branch>
          <Branch Name="16.3.2" Type="Service Pack">
            <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-217255">Cisco IOS XE Software 16.3 16.3.2</FullProductName>
          </Branch>
          <Branch Name="16.3.3" Type="Service Pack">
            <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-217256">Cisco IOS XE Software 16.3 16.3.3</FullProductName>
          </Branch>
          <Branch Name="16.3.1a" Type="Service Pack">
            <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-220802">Cisco IOS XE Software 16.3 16.3.1a</FullProductName>
          </Branch>
          <Branch Name="16.3.4" Type="Service Pack">
            <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-222711">Cisco IOS XE Software 16.3 16.3.4</FullProductName>
          </Branch>
        </Branch>
        <Branch Name="16.4" Type="Product Version">
          <Branch Name="16.4.1" Type="Service Pack">
            <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-214051">Cisco IOS XE Software 16.4 16.4.1</FullProductName>
          </Branch>
          <Branch Name="16.4.2" Type="Service Pack">
            <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-217257">Cisco IOS XE Software 16.4 16.4.2</FullProductName>
          </Branch>
        </Branch>
        <Branch Name="16.5" Type="Product Version">
          <Branch Name="16.5.1" Type="Service Pack">
            <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-217259">Cisco IOS XE Software 16.5 16.5.1</FullProductName>
          </Branch>
          <Branch Name="16.5.1a" Type="Service Pack">
            <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-225784">Cisco IOS XE Software 16.5 16.5.1a</FullProductName>
          </Branch>
          <Branch Name="16.5.1b" Type="Service Pack">
            <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-226330">Cisco IOS XE Software 16.5 16.5.1b</FullProductName>
          </Branch>
          <Branch Name="16.5.2" Type="Service Pack">
            <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-229187">Cisco IOS XE Software 16.5 16.5.2</FullProductName>
          </Branch>
        </Branch>
        <Branch Name="3.18SP" Type="Product Version">
          <Branch Name="3.18.3bSP" Type="Service Pack">
            <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-231826">Cisco IOS XE Software 3.18SP 3.18.3bSP</FullProductName>
          </Branch>
        </Branch>
        <Branch Name="16.6" Type="Product Version">
          <Branch Name="16.6.1" Type="Service Pack">
            <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-218901">Cisco IOS XE Software 16.6 16.6.1</FullProductName>
          </Branch>
        </Branch>
        <Branch Name="16.9" Type="Product Version">
          <Branch Name="16.9.1b" Type="Service Pack">
            <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-243362">Cisco IOS XE Software 16.9 16.9.1b</FullProductName>
          </Branch>
        </Branch>
        <Branch Name="16.13" Type="Product Version">
          <Branch Name="16.13.1" Type="Service Pack">
            <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-239363">Cisco IOS XE Software 16.13 16.13.1</FullProductName>
          </Branch>
        </Branch>
        <Branch Name="16.14" Type="Product Version">
          <Branch Name="16.14.1" Type="Service Pack">
            <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-239365">Cisco IOS XE Software 16.14 16.14.1</FullProductName>
          </Branch>
        </Branch>
        <Branch Name="16.15" Type="Product Version">
          <Branch Name="16.15.1" Type="Service Pack">
            <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-239367">Cisco IOS XE Software 16.15 16.15.1</FullProductName>
          </Branch>
        </Branch>
      </Branch>
    </Branch>
  </ProductTree>
  <Vulnerability Ordinal="1" xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/vuln">
    <Title>Cisco IOS XE Software Web UI Remote Access Privilege Escalation Vulnerability</Title>
    <ID SystemName="Cisco Bug ID">CSCvf71769</ID>
    <Notes>
      <Note Title="Summary" Type="Summary" Ordinal="1">A vulnerability in the web-based user interface (web UI) of Cisco IOS XE Software could allow an authenticated, remote attacker to gain elevated privileges on an affected device.



The vulnerability exists because the affected software does not reset the privilege level for each web UI session. An attacker who has valid credentials for an affected device could exploit this vulnerability by remotely accessing a VTY line to the device. A successful exploit could allow the attacker to access an affected device with the privileges of the user who previously logged in to the web UI.</Note>
      <Note Title="Cisco Bug IDs" Type="Other" Ordinal="2">CSCvf71769</Note>
    </Notes>
    <CVE>CVE-2018-0152</CVE>
    <ProductStatuses>
      <Status Type="Known Affected">
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-212436</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-213100</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-213809</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-213960</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-214051</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-214993</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-217253</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-217255</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-217256</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-217257</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-217259</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-218901</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-220802</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-222711</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-225784</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-226330</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-229187</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-231826</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-239363</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-239365</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-239367</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-243362</ProductID>
      </Status>
    </ProductStatuses>
    <CVSSScoreSets>
      <ScoreSetV3>
        <BaseScoreV3>8.8</BaseScoreV3>
        <VectorV3>CVSS:3.0/AV:N/AC:L/PR:L/UI:N/S:U/C:H/I:H/A:H</VectorV3>
      </ScoreSetV3>
    </CVSSScoreSets>
    <Remediations>
      <Remediation Type="Workaround">
        <Description>There are no workarounds that address this vulnerability.

Administrators who do not require the web UI may mitigate this vulnerability by disabling the HTTP Server feature on an affected device. To disable the feature, use the no ip http server and no ip http secure-server commands in the CLI.

Administrators who require the web UI may mitigate this vulnerability by enabling AAA authorization for EXEC sessions, locally or via a AAA server, for an affected device.</Description>
      </Remediation>
    </Remediations>
    <References>
      <Reference Type="Self">
        <URL>https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20180328-xepriv</URL>
        <Description>Cisco IOS XE Software Web UI Remote Access Privilege Escalation Vulnerability</Description>
      </Reference>
    </References>
  </Vulnerability>
</cvrfdoc>