<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cvrfdoc xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/cvrf">
  <DocumentTitle>Cisco FXOS and NX-OS Software Cisco Discovery Protocol Arbitrary Code Execution Vulnerability</DocumentTitle>
  <DocumentType>Cisco Security Advisory</DocumentType>
  <DocumentPublisher Type="Vendor">
    <ContactDetails>Emergency Support:
+1 877 228 7302 (toll-free within North America)
+1 408 525 6532 (International direct-dial)
Non-emergency Support:
Email: psirt@cisco.com
Support requests that are received via e-mail are typically acknowledged within 48 hours.</ContactDetails>
    <IssuingAuthority>Cisco product security incident response is the responsibility of the Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT). The Cisco PSIRT is a dedicated, global team that manages the receipt, investigation, and public reporting of security vulnerability information that is related to Cisco products and networks. The on-call Cisco PSIRT works 24x7 with Cisco customers, independent security researchers, consultants, industry organizations, and other vendors to identify possible security issues with Cisco products and networks.
More information can be found in Cisco Security Vulnerability Policy available at http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html</IssuingAuthority>
  </DocumentPublisher>
  <DocumentTracking>
    <Identification>
      <ID>cisco-sa-20180620-fxnxos-dos</ID>
    </Identification>
    <Status>Final</Status>
    <Version>1.1</Version>
    <RevisionHistory>
      <Revision>
        <Number>1.0</Number>
        <Date>2018-06-19T23:14:59</Date>
        <Description>Initial public release.</Description>
      </Revision>
      <Revision>
        <Number>1.1</Number>
        <Date>2018-07-05T21:11:59</Date>
        <Description>Updated the Fixed Release tables for FXOS and MDS.</Description>
      </Revision>
    </RevisionHistory>
    <InitialReleaseDate>2018-06-20T16:00:00</InitialReleaseDate>
    <CurrentReleaseDate>2018-07-05T21:11:59</CurrentReleaseDate>
    <Generator>
      <Engine>TVCE</Engine>
    </Generator>
  </DocumentTracking>
  <DocumentNotes>
    <Note Title="Summary" Type="Summary" Ordinal="1">A vulnerability in the Cisco Discovery Protocol component of Cisco FXOS Software and Cisco NX-OS Software could allow an unauthenticated, adjacent attacker to execute arbitrary code as root or cause a denial of service (DoS) condition on the affected device.

The vulnerability exists because of insufficiently validated Cisco Discovery Protocol packet headers. An attacker could exploit this vulnerability by sending a crafted Cisco Discovery Protocol packet to a Layer 2 adjacent affected device. A successful exploit could allow the attacker to cause a buffer overflow that could allow the attacker to execute arbitrary code as root or cause a DoS condition on the affected device.

Cisco has released software updates that address this vulnerability. There are no workarounds that address this vulnerability.

This advisory is available at the following link:
https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20180620-fxnxos-dos ["https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20180620-fxnxos-dos"]

This advisory is part of the June 2018 Cisco FXOS and NX-OS Software Security Advisory Collection, which includes 24 Cisco Security Advisories that describe 24 vulnerabilities. For a complete list of the advisories and links to them, see Cisco Event Response: June 2018 Cisco FXOS and NX-OS Software Security Advisory Collection ["https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/viewErp.x?alertId=ERP-67770"].</Note>
    <Note Title="Affected Products" Type="General" Ordinal="2" />
    <Note Title="Vulnerable Products" Type="General" Ordinal="3">This vulnerability affects the following Cisco products if they are running a vulnerable release of Cisco FXOS Software or Cisco NX-OS Software and are configured to use Cisco Discovery Protocol:

      Firepower 4100 Series Next-Generation Firewalls
      Firepower 9300 Security Appliance
      MDS 9000 Series Multilayer Switches
      Nexus 1000V Series Switches
      Nexus 1100 Series Cloud Services Platforms
      Nexus 2000 Series Fabric Extenders
      Nexus 3000 Series Switches
      Nexus 3500 Platform Switches
      Nexus 5500 Platform Switches
      Nexus 5600 Platform Switches
      Nexus 6000 Series Switches
      Nexus 7000 Series Switches
      Nexus 7700 Series Switches
      Nexus 9000 Series Fabric Switches in Application Centric Infrastructure (ACI) mode
      Nexus 9000 Series Switches in standalone NX-OS mode
      Nexus 9500 R-Series Line Cards and Fabric Modules
      UCS 6100 Series Fabric Interconnects
      UCS 6200 Series Fabric Interconnects
      UCS 6300 Series Fabric Interconnects

For information about which Cisco FXOS and NX-OS Software releases are vulnerable, see the Fixed Software ["#fs"] section of this advisory.
  Assessing the Cisco Discovery Protocol Configuration
Administrators can determine whether a device is configured to use Cisco Discovery Protocol by using the show cdp global command in the device CLI. If the device is configured to use Cisco Discovery Protocol, the output of the command will be similar to the following:


CLI(config)# show cdp global
Global CDP information:  CDP enabled globally  Refresh time is 60 seconds  Hold time is 180 seconds  CDPv2 advertisements is enabled  DeviceID TLV in System-Name(Default) Format

If only specific interfaces are configured to use Cisco Discovery Protocol, administrators can use the show cdp interface command in the device CLI to determine which interfaces are configured to use Cisco Discovery Protocol.
  Determining the Cisco FXOS Software Release
Administrators can check the release of Cisco FXOS Software that is running on a device by using the following commands in the device CLI or by navigating to the Overview tab in the Admin portal. The following example shows the output of the show version CLI command on a device that is running Cisco FXOS Software Release 2.2(2.14), as identified in the Package-Vers field of the command output:


QP4120B1 # scope system
QP4120B1 /system # show version  FPRM:  Running-Vers: 4.2(2.15)  Package-Vers: 2.2(2.14)  Activate-Status: Ready
  Determining the Cisco NX-OS Software Release
Administrators can check the release of Cisco NX-OS Software that is running on a device by using the show version command in the device CLI. The following example shows the output of this command on a device that is running Cisco NX-OS Software Release 7.3(2)D1(1):


nxos-switch# show version


Cisco Nexus Operating System (NX-OS) Software
TAC support: http://www.cisco.com/tac  Documents: http://www.cisco.com/en/US/products/ps9372/tsd_products_support_series_home.html  Copyright (c) 2002-2017, Cisco Systems, Inc. All rights reserved.  The copyrights to certain works contained in this software are  owned by other third parties and used and distributed under  license. Certain components of this software are licensed under  the GNU General Public License (GPL) version 2.0 or the GNU  Lesser General Public License (LGPL) Version 2.1. A copy of each  such license is available at  http://www.opensource.org/licenses/gpl-2.0.php and  http://www.opensource.org/licenses/lgpl-2.1.php  Software    BIOS:      version 2.12.0    kickstart: version 7.3(2)D1(1)    system:    version 7.3(2)D1(1)  .  .  .</Note>
    <Note Title="Products Confirmed Not Vulnerable" Type="General" Ordinal="4">Only products listed in the Vulnerable Products ["#vp"] section of this advisory are known to be affected by this vulnerability.

Cisco has confirmed that this vulnerability does not affect Cisco Firepower 2100 Series Firewalls or Cisco Nexus 3600 Platform Switches.

Cisco has not investigated whether this vulnerability affects Cisco Nexus 4000 Series Switches, Cisco Nexus 5010 Switches, or Cisco Nexus 5020 Switches because those products have reached end-of-life status. For more information, refer to the End-of-Sale and End-of-Life Announcement for the Cisco Nexus 4000 Series Switch Modules for IBM BladeCenter ["https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/products/collateral/switches/nexus-4000-series-switches/eos-eol-notice-c51-733205.html"] and the End-of-Sale and End-of-Life Announcement for the Cisco Nexus 5010 and Nexus 5020 Switches ["https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/products/collateral/switches/nexus-5000-series-switches/eol_c51-709037.html"].</Note>
    <Note Title="Workarounds" Type="General" Ordinal="5">There are no workarounds that address this vulnerability.</Note>
    <Note Title="Fixed Software" Type="General" Ordinal="6">Cisco has released free software updates that address the vulnerability described in this advisory. Customers may only install and expect support for software versions and feature sets for which they have purchased a license. By installing, downloading, accessing, or otherwise using such software upgrades, customers agree to follow the terms of the Cisco software license:
https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/products/end-user-license-agreement.html ["https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/products/end-user-license-agreement.html"]

Additionally, customers may only download software for which they have a valid license, procured from Cisco directly, or through a Cisco authorized reseller or partner. In most cases this will be a maintenance upgrade to software that was previously purchased. Free security software updates do not entitle customers to a new software license, additional software feature sets, or major revision upgrades.

When considering software upgrades, customers are advised to regularly consult the advisories for Cisco products, which are available from the Cisco Security Advisories and Alerts page ["https://www.cisco.com/go/psirt"], to determine exposure and a complete upgrade solution.

In all cases, customers should ensure that the devices to be upgraded contain sufficient memory and confirm that current hardware and software configurations will continue to be supported properly by the new release. If the information is not clear, customers are advised to contact the Cisco Technical Assistance Center (TAC) or their contracted maintenance providers.
  Customers Without Service Contracts
Customers who purchase directly from Cisco but do not hold a Cisco service contract and customers who make purchases through third-party vendors but are unsuccessful in obtaining fixed software through their point of sale should obtain upgrades by contacting the Cisco TAC:
https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/support/web/tsd-cisco-worldwide-contacts.html ["https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/support/web/tsd-cisco-worldwide-contacts.html"]

Customers should have the product serial number available and be prepared to provide the URL of this advisory as evidence of entitlement to a free upgrade.
  Fixed Releases
Customers are advised to upgrade to an appropriate release as indicated in the applicable table in this section. To help ensure a complete upgrade solution, consider that this advisory is part of a collection. For a complete list of the advisories in the collection and links to them, see Cisco Event Response: June 2018 Cisco FXOS and NX-OS Software Security Advisory Collection ["http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/viewErp.x?alertId=ERP-67770"].

In the following tables, the left column lists releases of Cisco FXOS or NX-OS Software. The center column indicates whether a release is affected by the vulnerability described in this advisory and the first release that includes the fix for this vulnerability. The right column indicates whether a release is affected by all the vulnerabilities described in this collection of advisories and which release includes fixes for those vulnerabilities.

Firepower 4100 Series Next-Generation Firewalls: CSCvc22202 ["https://bst.cloudapps.cisco.com/bugsearch/bug/CSCvc22202"]
                                Cisco FXOS Software Release
              First Fixed Release for This Vulnerability              First Fixed Release for All Vulnerabilities Described in the Collection of Advisories                                               1.1
              1.1.4.169
              2.0.1.159                                  2.0              2.0.1.135
              2.0.1.159
                                  2.1               2.1.1.73
              2.1.1.86
                                  2.2              Not vulnerable
              2.2.2.17 or 2.3.1.58
                                  2.3               Not vulnerable
              Not vulnerable

Firepower 9300 Security Appliance: CSCvc22202 ["https://bst.cloudapps.cisco.com/bugsearch/bug/CSCvc22202"]
                                Cisco FXOS Software Release
              First Fixed Release for This Vulnerability              First Fixed Release for All Vulnerabilities Described in the Collection of Advisories                                               1.1
              1.1.4.169
              2.0.1.159
                                  2.0              2.0.1.135
              2.0.1.159
                                  2.1              2.1.1.73              2.1.1.86                                  2.2               Not vulnerable
              2.2.2.17 or 2.3.1.58
                                  2.3               Not vulnerable
              Not vulnerable

MDS 9000 Series Multilayer Switches: CSCvc88150   ["https://bst.cloudapps.cisco.com/bugsearch/bug/CSCvc88150"]
                                Cisco NX-OS Software Release
              First Fixed Release for This Vulnerability              First Fixed Release for All Vulnerabilities Described in the Collection of Advisories                                               5.2               8.1(1)
              8.1(1a) or 8.2(1)
                                  6.2               8.1(1)
              8.1(1a) or 8.2(1)
                                  7.3               8.1(1)
              8.1(1a) or 8.2(1)
                                  8.1               Not vulnerable
              8.1(1a) or 8.2(1)
                                  8.2               Not vulnerable
              Not vulnerable

  Nexus 1000V Series Switches and Nexus 1100 Series Cloud Services Platforms: CSCvc88159 ["https://bst.cloudapps.cisco.com/bugsearch/bug/CSCvc88159"]
                                Cisco NX-OS Software Release
              First Fixed Release for This Vulnerability              First Fixed Release for All Vulnerabilities Described in the Collection of Advisories                                               Prior to 5.2
              5.2(1)SV3(3.1)
              5.2(1)SV3(3.15)
                                  5.2               5.2(1)SV3(3.1)
              5.2(1)SV3(3.15)

Nexus 3000 Series Switches:CSCvc88078 ["https://bst.cloudapps.cisco.com/bugsearch/bug/CSCvc88078"]
                                Cisco NX-OS Software Release
              First Fixed Release for This Vulnerability              First Fixed Release for All Vulnerabilities Described in the Collection of Advisories                                               Prior to 7.0(3)I4
              7.0(3)I4(6)
              7.0(3)I7(4)
                                  7.0(3)I4
              7.0(3)I4(6)
              7.0(3)I7(4)
                                  7.0(3)I5
              7.0(3)I5(2)
              7.0(3)I7(4)
                                  7.0(3)I6
              Not vulnerable
              7.0(3)I7(4)
                                  7.0(3)I7              Not vulnerable
              7.0(3)I7(4)

Nexus 3500 Platform Switches: CSCvc88078 ["https://bst.cloudapps.cisco.com/bugsearch/bug/CSCvc88078"]
                                Cisco NX-OS Software Release
              First Fixed Release for This Vulnerability              First Fixed Release for All Vulnerabilities Described in the Collection of Advisories                                               6.0              6.0(2)A8(5)
              7.0(3)I7(4)
                                  7.0               Not vulnerable
              7.0(3)I7(4)

Nexus 2000, 5500, 5600, and 6000 Series Switches: CSCvc22205 ["https://bst.cloudapps.cisco.com/bugsearch/bug/CSCvc22205"]
                                Cisco NX-OS Software Release
              First Fixed Release for This Vulnerability              First Fixed Release for All Vulnerabilities Described in the Collection of Advisories                                               6.0
              7.3(2)N1(1)
              7.3(3)N1(1)
                                  7.0              7.3(2)N1(1)
              7.3(3)N1(1)
                                  7.1              7.3(2)N1(1)
              7.3(3)N1(1)
                                  7.2              7.3(2)N1(1)
              7.3(3)N1(1)
                                  7.3              7.3(2)N1(1)
              7.3(3)N1(1)

Nexus 7000 and 7700 Series Switches: CSCvc88150 ["https://bst.cloudapps.cisco.com/bugsearch/bug/CSCvc88150"]
                                Cisco NX-OS Software Release
              First Fixed Release for This Vulnerability              First Fixed Release for All Vulnerabilities Described in the Collection of Advisories                                               6.2              6.2(20)
              8.1(2) or 8.2(1)
                                  7.2              7.3(2)D1(1)
              8.1(2) or 8.2(1)
                                  7.3               7.3(2)D1(1)
              8.1(2) or 8.2(1)
                                  8.0               8.1(1)
              8.1(2) or 8.2(1)
                                  8.1               Not vulnerable
              8.1(2) or 8.2(1)
                                  8.2               Not vulnerable
              Not vulnerable

Nexus 9000 Series Switches in ACI mode: CSCvc88162 ["https://bst.cloudapps.cisco.com/bugsearch/bug/CSCvc88162"]
                                    Cisco NX-OS Software Release
              First Fixed Release for This Vulnerability              First Fixed Release for All Vulnerabilities Described in the Collection of Advisories                                               Prior to 12.1 / 2.1&gt;              12.2(2e) / 2.2(2e)
              13.1(1i) / 3.1(1i)
                                  12.1 / 2.1              12.2(2e) / 2.2(2e)
              13.1(1i) / 3.1(1i)
                                  12.2 / 2.2              12.2(2e) / 2.2(2e)
              13.1(1i) / 3.1(1i)
                                  12.3 / 2.3              Not vulnerable
              13.1(1i) / 3.1(1i)
                                  13.0 / 3.0              Not vulnerable
              13.1(1i) / 3.1(1i)
                                  13.1 / 3.1              Not vulnerable
              13.1(1i) / 3.1(1i)

Nexus 9000 Series Switches in standalone NX-OS mode: CSCvc88078 ["https://bst.cloudapps.cisco.com/bugsearch/bug/CSCvc88078"]
                                    Cisco NX-OS Software Release
              First Fixed Release for This Vulnerability              First Fixed Release for All Vulnerabilities Described in the Collection of Advisories                                               Prior to 7.0(3)I4
              7.0(3)I4(6)
              7.0(3)I7(4)
                                  7.0(3)I4              7.0(3)I4(6)
              7.0(3)I7(4)
                                  7.0(3)I5              7.0(3)I5(2)
              7.0(3)I7(4)
                                  7.0(3)I6              Not vulnerable
              7.0(3)I7(4)
                                  7.0(3)I7              Not vulnerable
              7.0(3)I7(4)

Nexus 9500 R-Series Line Cards and Fabric Modules: CSCvc88167 ["https://bst.cloudapps.cisco.com/bugsearch/bug/CSCvc88167"]
                                Cisco NX-OS Software Release
              First Fixed Release for This Vulnerability              First Fixed Release for All Vulnerabilities Described in the Collection of Advisories                                               7.0              7.0(3)F2(1)
              7.0(3)F3(3a)

 UCS 6100, 6200, and 6300 Series Fabric Interconnects: CSCvc22208 ["https://bst.cloudapps.cisco.com/bugsearch/bug/CSCvc22208"]
                                Cisco NX-OS Software Release
              First Fixed Release for This Vulnerability              First Fixed Release for All Vulnerabilities Described in the Collection of Advisories                                               Prior to 2.2               3.1(3a)
              3.2(2b)
                                  2.2              3.1(3a)
              3.2(2b)
                                  2.5              3.1(3a)
              3.2(2b)
                                  3.0              3.1(3a)
              3.2(2b)
                                  3.1               3.1(3a)
              3.2(2b)
                                  3.2               Not vulnerable
              3.2(2b)</Note>
    <Note Title="Vulnerability Policy" Type="General" Ordinal="7">To learn about Cisco security vulnerability disclosure policies and publications, see the Security Vulnerability Policy ["http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html"]. This document also contains instructions for obtaining fixed software and receiving security vulnerability information from Cisco.</Note>
    <Note Title="Exploitation and Public Announcements" Type="General" Ordinal="8">The Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT) is not aware of any public announcements or malicious use of the vulnerability that is described in this advisory.</Note>
    <Note Title="Source" Type="General" Ordinal="9">This vulnerability was found during internal security testing.</Note>
    <Note Title="Legal Disclaimer" Type="Legal Disclaimer" Ordinal="10">THIS DOCUMENT IS PROVIDED ON AN "AS IS" BASIS AND DOES NOT IMPLY ANY KIND OF GUARANTEE OR WARRANTY, INCLUDING THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY OR FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR USE. YOUR USE OF THE INFORMATION ON THE DOCUMENT OR MATERIALS LINKED FROM THE DOCUMENT IS AT YOUR OWN RISK. CISCO RESERVES THE RIGHT TO CHANGE OR UPDATE THIS DOCUMENT AT ANY TIME.

A standalone copy or paraphrase of the text of this document that omits the distribution URL is an uncontrolled copy and may lack important information or contain factual errors. The information in this document is intended for end users of Cisco products.</Note>
  </DocumentNotes>
  <DocumentReferences>
    <Reference Type="Self">
      <URL>https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20180620-fxnxos-dos</URL>
      <Description>Cisco FXOS and NX-OS Software Cisco Discovery Protocol Arbitrary Code Execution Vulnerability</Description>
    </Reference>
    <Reference>
      <URL>http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/viewErp.x?alertId=ERP-67770</URL>
      <Description>Cisco Event Response: June 2018 Cisco FXOS and NX-OS Software Security Advisory Collection</Description>
    </Reference>
    <Reference>
      <URL>http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/viewErp.x?alertId=ERP-67770</URL>
      <Description>Cisco Event Response: June 2018 Cisco FXOS and NX-OS Software Security Advisory Collection</Description>
    </Reference>
  </DocumentReferences>
  <ProductTree xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/prod">
    <Branch Name="Cisco" Type="Vendor">
      <Branch Name="Cisco NX-OS Software" Type="Product Name">
        <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-80720">Cisco NX-OS Software </FullProductName>
      </Branch>
      <Branch Name="Cisco Unified Computing System (Managed)" Type="Product Name">
        <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-112776">Cisco Unified Computing System (Managed) </FullProductName>
      </Branch>
      <Branch Name="Cisco Firepower Extensible Operating System (FXOS)" Type="Product Name">
        <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-225888">Cisco Firepower Extensible Operating System (FXOS) </FullProductName>
      </Branch>
    </Branch>
  </ProductTree>
  <Vulnerability Ordinal="1" xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/vuln">
    <Title>Cisco FXOS and NX-OS System Software Cisco Discovery Protocol Denial of Service Vulnerability</Title>
    <ID SystemName="Cisco Bug ID">CSCvc22202</ID>
    <Notes>
      <Note Title="Summary" Type="Summary" Ordinal="1">A vulnerability in the Cisco Discovery Protocol component of Cisco FXOS Software and Cisco NX-OS Software could allow an unauthenticated, adjacent attacker to execute arbitrary code as root or cause a denial of service (DoS) condition on the affected device.

The vulnerability exists because of insufficiently validated Cisco Discovery Protocol packet headers. An attacker could exploit this vulnerability by sending a crafted Cisco Discovery Protocol packet to a Layer 2 adjacent affected device. A successful exploit could allow the attacker to cause a buffer overflow that could allow the attacker to execute arbitrary code as root or cause a DoS condition on the affected device.
</Note>
      <Note Title="Cisco Bug IDs" Type="Other" Ordinal="2">CSCvc22202,CSCvc22205,CSCvc88078,CSCvc88167,CSCvc88150,CSCvc88162,CSCvc88159,CSCvc22208</Note>
    </Notes>
    <CVE>CVE-2018-0303</CVE>
    <ProductStatuses>
      <Status Type="Known Affected">
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-225888</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-80720</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-112776</ProductID>
      </Status>
    </ProductStatuses>
    <CVSSScoreSets>
      <ScoreSetV3>
        <BaseScoreV3>7.5</BaseScoreV3>
        <VectorV3>CVSS:3.0/AV:A/AC:H/PR:N/UI:N/S:U/C:H/I:H/A:H</VectorV3>
      </ScoreSetV3>
    </CVSSScoreSets>
    <Remediations>
      <Remediation Type="Workaround">
        <Description>There are no workarounds that address this vulnerability.</Description>
      </Remediation>
    </Remediations>
    <References>
      <Reference Type="Self">
        <URL>https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20180620-fxnxos-dos</URL>
        <Description>Cisco FXOS and NX-OS Software Cisco Discovery Protocol Arbitrary Code Execution Vulnerability</Description>
      </Reference>
    </References>
  </Vulnerability>
</cvrfdoc>