<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cvrfdoc xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/cvrf">
  <DocumentTitle>Cisco Firepower Detection Engine SSL Decryption Memory Consumption Denial of Service Vulnerability </DocumentTitle>
  <DocumentType>Cisco Security Advisory</DocumentType>
  <DocumentPublisher Type="Vendor">
    <ContactDetails>Emergency Support:
+1 877 228 7302 (toll-free within North America)
+1 408 525 6532 (International direct-dial)
Non-emergency Support:
Email: psirt@cisco.com
Support requests that are received via e-mail are typically acknowledged within 48 hours.</ContactDetails>
    <IssuingAuthority>Cisco product security incident response is the responsibility of the Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT). The Cisco PSIRT is a dedicated, global team that manages the receipt, investigation, and public reporting of security vulnerability information that is related to Cisco products and networks. The on-call Cisco PSIRT works 24x7 with Cisco customers, independent security researchers, consultants, industry organizations, and other vendors to identify possible security issues with Cisco products and networks.
More information can be found in Cisco Security Vulnerability Policy available at http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html</IssuingAuthority>
  </DocumentPublisher>
  <DocumentTracking>
    <Identification>
      <ID>cisco-sa-20171004-ftd</ID>
    </Identification>
    <Status>Final</Status>
    <Version>1.0</Version>
    <RevisionHistory>
      <Revision>
        <Number>1.0</Number>
        <Date>2017-10-04T15:17:18</Date>
        <Description>Initial public release.</Description>
      </Revision>
    </RevisionHistory>
    <InitialReleaseDate>2017-10-04T16:00:00</InitialReleaseDate>
    <CurrentReleaseDate>2017-10-04T15:17:18</CurrentReleaseDate>
    <Generator>
      <Engine>TVCE</Engine>
    </Generator>
  </DocumentTracking>
  <DocumentNotes>
    <Note Title="Summary" Type="Summary" Ordinal="1">A vulnerability in SSL traffic decryption for Cisco Firepower Threat Defense (FTD) Software could allow an unauthenticated, remote attacker to cause depletion of system memory. If this memory leak persists over time, a denial of service (DoS) condition could develop because traffic can cease to be forwarded through the device.

The vulnerability is due to an error in how the Firepower Detection Snort Engine handles SSL traffic decryption and notifications to and from the Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) handler. An attacker could exploit this vulnerability by sending a steady stream of malicious Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) traffic through the device. An exploit could allow the attacker to cause a DoS condition when the device runs low on system memory.

Cisco has released software updates that address this vulnerability. There are no workarounds that address this vulnerability.

This advisory is available at the following link:
https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20171004-ftd ["https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20171004-ftd"]</Note>
    <Note Title="Vulnerable Products" Type="General" Ordinal="2">This vulnerability affects Cisco Firepower Threat Defense (FTD) Software Releases 6.0.1 and later when the software is configured as described in this section and is running on any of the following Cisco products:

Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) 5500-X Series Next-Generation Firewalls
Firepower 2100 Series Security Appliances
Firepower 4100 Series Security Appliances
Firepower 9300 Series Security Appliances

Affected devices are vulnerable when they are configured for one or more SSL inspection policies for Decrypt and Resign ["http://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/support/docs/security/firesight-management-center/200202-Configuration-of-an-SSL-Inspection-Polic.html#anc4"] or Known Key ["https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/support/docs/security/firesight-management-center/200202-Configuration-of-an-SSL-Inspection-Polic.html#anc9"]. These features allow the SSL traffic to be decrypted on the device for further inspection.

This vulnerability applies to FTD-supported releases only. These releases contain both Firepower and ASA code. Review Firepower Threat Defense Devices ["http://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/td/docs/security/firepower/compatibility/firepower-compatibility.html#reference_070E1908889545BDB6CC564676202628"] in the Cisco Firepower Compatibility Guide ["http://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/td/docs/security/firepower/compatibility/firepower-compatibility.html"] for additional information.

Administrators can use the CLI command show version to determine the FTD release. In this example, the device is running software release 6.2.0.


&gt; show version
---------------------[ ftd ]---------------------
Model                     : Cisco ASA5525-X Threat Defense (75) Version 6.2.0 (Build 362)
UUID                      : 2849ba3c-ecb8-11e6-98ca-b9fc2975893c
Rules update version      : 2017-03-15-001-vrt
VDB version               : 279
----------------------------------------------------</Note>
    <Note Title="Products Confirmed Not Vulnerable" Type="General" Ordinal="3">No other Cisco products are currently known to be affected by this vulnerability.

Cisco has confirmed that this vulnerability does not affect the following Cisco products:

3000 Series Industrial Security Appliances (ISA)
Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) 5000-X Series with FirePOWER Services
Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) 5500-X Series with FirePOWER Services
Advanced Malware Protection (AMP) for Networks, 7000 Series Appliances
Advanced Malware Protection (AMP) for Networks, 8000 Series Appliances
FirePOWER 7000 Series Appliances
FirePOWER 8000 Series Appliances
Firepower Management Center
Firepower Threat Defense for Integrated Services Routers (ISRs)
Intrusion Prevention System (IPS) Software
Virtual Next-Generation Intrusion Prevention System (NGIPSv) for VMware</Note>
    <Note Title="Details" Type="General" Ordinal="4">Cisco FTD is a unified software image that includes the ASA features and Firepower services. This unified software is capable of offering the function of ASA and Firepower in one platform, both in terms of hardware and software features.</Note>
    <Note Title="Indicators of Compromise" Type="General" Ordinal="5">Vulnerable devices are compromised when all the following conditions are met:

The device stops forwarding traffic.
The output of the show blocks command shows a zero count of a particular memory block. This is most common for the memory blocks of size 2048 or 9344.
firepower# show blocks
  SIZE    MAX    LOW    CNT
0   1450   1448   1450       4    100     99     99
80   1000    950    984     256   4148   3898   4040    1550   6279   6184   6258    2048    15864           0            0    2560    164    164    164    4096    100    100    100    8192    100    100    100    9344    100    100    100   16384    102    102    102   65536     16     16     16

The output of the debug command show asp inspect-dp snort queues detail debug shows the Receive Queue Utilization—RxQ (util)—at 100 percent.
firepower# show asp inspect-dp snort queues detail debug
SNORT Inspect Instance Queue Configuration    RxQ-Size:              1   MB
TxQ-Size:            128   KB
TxQ-Data-Limit:      102.4 KB   (80%)
TxQ-Data-Hi-Thresh:   35.8 KB   (28%)  Id QId  RxQ        RxQ    RxQ        RxQ              TxQ        TxQ    TxQ        TxQ
(used)     (util) (max used) (state)          (used)     (util) (max used) (state)            -- ---- ---------- ------ ---------- ---------------- ---------- ------ ---------- --------   0  [0]    2   MB   100%     2   MB   READY              0        0%       2.1 KB   READY

The output of the debug command show asp inspect-dp snort counters debug zeros shows a count for Receive Queue Full (RxQ-Full) that is not zero.
firepower# show asp inspect-dp snort counters debug zeros
SNORT Inspect Instance Counters

Id   QId  Type  Name                           Value      Raw-Value
--   ---- ----  ----                           ---------- ----------
...
All  All  drop  RxQ-Full                       146.5 K    (146546)
All  All  drop  TxQ-Full                         0        (0)


Contact the Cisco Technical Assistance Center (TAC) if additional assistance is required to determine whether the device has been compromised by exploitation of this vulnerability.</Note>
    <Note Title="Workarounds" Type="General" Ordinal="6">There are no workarounds that address this vulnerability.</Note>
    <Note Title="Fixed Software" Type="General" Ordinal="7">Cisco has released free software updates that address the vulnerability described in this advisory. Customers may only install and expect support for software versions and feature sets for which they have purchased a license. By installing, downloading, accessing, or otherwise using such software upgrades, customers agree to follow the terms of the Cisco software license:  https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/products/end-user-license-agreement.html ["https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/products/end-user-license-agreement.html"]

Additionally, customers may only download software for which they have a valid license, procured from Cisco directly, or through a Cisco authorized reseller or partner. In most cases this will be a maintenance upgrade to software that was previously purchased. Free security software updates do not entitle customers to a new software license, additional software feature sets, or major revision upgrades.

When considering software upgrades, customers are advised to regularly consult the advisories for Cisco products, which are available from the Cisco Security Advisories and Alerts page ["https://www.cisco.com/go/psirt"], to determine exposure and a complete upgrade solution.

In all cases, customers should ensure that the devices to be upgraded contain sufficient memory and confirm that current hardware and software configurations will continue to be supported properly by the new release. If the information is not clear, customers are advised to contact the Cisco TAC or their contracted maintenance providers.

Customers Without Service Contracts

Customers who purchase directly from Cisco but do not hold a Cisco service contract and customers who make purchases through third-party vendors but are unsuccessful in obtaining fixed software through their point of sale should obtain upgrades by contacting the Cisco TAC: https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/support/web/tsd-cisco-worldwide-contacts.html ["https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/support/web/tsd-cisco-worldwide-contacts.html"]

Customers should have the product serial number available and be prepared to provide the URL of this advisory as evidence of entitlement to a free upgrade.

Fixed Releases

Customers should upgrade to an appropriate release as indicated in the table in this section. To help ensure a complete upgrade solution, consider that this advisory is part of a collection that includes the following advisories:

cisco-sa-20171004-fpsnort ["https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20171004-fpsnort"]: Cisco Firepower Detection Engine IPv6 Denial of Service Vulnerability
cisco-sa-20171004-ftd ["https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20171004-ftd"]: Cisco Firepower Detection Engine SSL Decryption Memory Consumption Denial of Service Vulnerability

In the following table, the left column lists major releases of Cisco software. The center column indicates whether a major release is affected by the vulnerability described in this advisory and the first minor release that includes the fix for this vulnerability. The right column indicates whether a major release is affected by all the vulnerabilities described in this collection of advisories and the current recommended release for those vulnerabilities.
                                Cisco Firepower Threat Defense Software                             First Fixed Release for              This Vulnerability                              Recommended Release for              This Vulnerability and All Vulnerabilities Described in the Collection of Advisories                                                 Prior to 6.0
              Not supported
              N/A
                                  6.0.1
              Vulnerable; migrate to 6.2.0.2
              6.2.0.2
                                  6.1.0              6.1.0.6 (future release)
              6.1.0.6 (future release) or 6.2.0.2                                   6.2.0              6.2.0.2 or later
              6.2.0.3                                   6.2.1               Vulnerable; migrate to 6.2.2               6.2.2
                                  6.2.2              6.2.2               6.2.2</Note>
    <Note Title="Vulnerability Policy" Type="General" Ordinal="8">To learn about Cisco security vulnerability disclosure policies and publications, see the Security Vulnerability Policy ["http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html"]. This document also contains instructions for obtaining fixed software and receiving security vulnerability information from Cisco.</Note>
    <Note Title="Exploitation and Public Announcements" Type="General" Ordinal="9">The Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT) is not aware of any public announcements or malicious use of the vulnerability that is described in this advisory.</Note>
    <Note Title="Source" Type="General" Ordinal="10">This vulnerability was found during resolution of a Cisco TAC support case.</Note>
    <Note Title="Legal Disclaimer" Type="Legal Disclaimer" Ordinal="11">THIS DOCUMENT IS PROVIDED ON AN "AS IS" BASIS AND DOES NOT IMPLY ANY KIND OF GUARANTEE OR WARRANTY, INCLUDING THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY OR FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR USE. YOUR USE OF THE INFORMATION ON THE DOCUMENT OR MATERIALS LINKED FROM THE DOCUMENT IS AT YOUR OWN RISK. CISCO RESERVES THE RIGHT TO CHANGE OR UPDATE THIS DOCUMENT AT ANY TIME.

A standalone copy or paraphrase of the text of this document that omits the distribution URL is an uncontrolled copy and may lack important information or contain factual errors. The information in this document is intended for end users of Cisco products.</Note>
  </DocumentNotes>
  <DocumentReferences>
    <Reference Type="Self">
      <URL>https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20171004-ftd</URL>
      <Description>Cisco Firepower Detection Engine SSL Decryption Memory Consumption Denial of Service Vulnerability </Description>
    </Reference>
  </DocumentReferences>
  <ProductTree xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/prod">
    <Branch Name="Cisco" Type="Vendor">
      <Branch Name="Cisco Firepower Threat Defense Software" Type="Product Name">
        <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-220203">Cisco Firepower Threat Defense Software </FullProductName>
      </Branch>
    </Branch>
  </ProductTree>
  <Vulnerability Ordinal="1" xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/vuln">
    <Title>Cisco Firepower Detection Engine SSL Decryption Memory Consumption Denial of Service Vulnerability</Title>
    <ID SystemName="Cisco Bug ID">CSCve02069</ID>
    <Notes>
      <Note Title="Summary" Type="Summary" Ordinal="1">A vulnerability in SSL traffic decryption for Cisco Firepower Threat Defense (FTD) Software could allow an unauthenticated, remote attacker to cause depletion of system memory. If this memory leak persists over time, a denial of service (DoS) condition could develop because traffic can cease to be forwarded through the device.

The vulnerability is due to an error in how the Firepower Detection Snort Engine handles SSL traffic decryption and notifications to and from the Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) handler. An attacker could exploit this vulnerability by sending a steady stream of malicious Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) traffic through the device. An exploit could allow the attacker to cause a DoS condition when the device runs low on system memory.
</Note>
      <Note Title="Cisco Bug IDs" Type="Other" Ordinal="2">CSCve02069</Note>
    </Notes>
    <CVE>CVE-2017-12245</CVE>
    <ProductStatuses>
      <Status Type="Known Affected">
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-220203</ProductID>
      </Status>
    </ProductStatuses>
    <CVSSScoreSets>
      <ScoreSetV3>
        <BaseScoreV3>8.6</BaseScoreV3>
        <VectorV3>CVSS:3.0/AV:N/AC:L/PR:N/UI:N/S:C/C:N/I:N/A:H</VectorV3>
      </ScoreSetV3>
    </CVSSScoreSets>
    <Remediations>
      <Remediation Type="Workaround">
        <Description>There are no workarounds that address this vulnerability.</Description>
      </Remediation>
    </Remediations>
    <References>
      <Reference Type="Self">
        <URL>https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20171004-ftd</URL>
        <Description>Cisco Firepower Detection Engine SSL Decryption Memory Consumption Denial of Service Vulnerability </Description>
      </Reference>
    </References>
  </Vulnerability>
</cvrfdoc>