<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cvrfdoc xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/cvrf">
  <DocumentTitle>Cisco ASA Software Internet Key Exchange Version 1 XAUTH Denial of Service Vulnerability</DocumentTitle>
  <DocumentType>Cisco Security Advisory</DocumentType>
  <DocumentPublisher Type="Vendor">
    <ContactDetails>Emergency Support:
+1 877 228 7302 (toll-free within North America)
+1 408 525 6532 (International direct-dial)
Non-emergency Support:
Email: psirt@cisco.com
Support requests that are received via e-mail are typically acknowledged within 48 hours.</ContactDetails>
    <IssuingAuthority>Cisco product security incident response is the responsibility of the Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT). The Cisco PSIRT is a dedicated, global team that manages the receipt, investigation, and public reporting of security vulnerability information that is related to Cisco products and networks. The on-call Cisco PSIRT works 24x7 with Cisco customers, independent security researchers, consultants, industry organizations, and other vendors to identify possible security issues with Cisco products and networks.
More information can be found in Cisco Security Vulnerability Policy available at http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html</IssuingAuthority>
  </DocumentPublisher>
  <DocumentTracking>
    <Identification>
      <ID>cisco-sa-20170419-asa-xauth</ID>
    </Identification>
    <Status>Final</Status>
    <Version>1.0</Version>
    <RevisionHistory>
      <Revision>
        <Number>1.0</Number>
        <Date>2017-04-19T15:20:13</Date>
        <Description>Initial public release.</Description>
      </Revision>
    </RevisionHistory>
    <InitialReleaseDate>2017-04-19T16:00:00</InitialReleaseDate>
    <CurrentReleaseDate>2017-04-19T15:20:13</CurrentReleaseDate>
    <Generator>
      <Engine>TVCE</Engine>
    </Generator>
  </DocumentTracking>
  <DocumentNotes>
    <Note Title="Summary" Type="Summary" Ordinal="1">A vulnerability in the Internet Key Exchange Version 1 (IKEv1) XAUTH code of Cisco ASA Software could allow  an authenticated, remote attacker to cause a reload of an affected  system.

The vulnerability is due to insufficient validation of  the IKEv1 XAUTH parameters passed during an IKEv1 negotiation. An attacker  could exploit this vulnerability by sending crafted parameters.

Note: Only traffic directed to the affected system can  be used to exploit this vulnerability. This vulnerability only affects  systems configured in routed firewall mode and in single or  multiple context mode. This vulnerability can be triggered by IPv4 or  IPv6 traffic. A valid IKEv1 Phase 1 needs to be established to exploit this vulnerability, which means that an attacker would need to have knowledge of a pre-shared key or have a valid certificate for phase 1 authentication.

Cisco has released software updates that address this vulnerability. There are no workarounds that address this vulnerability.

This advisory is available at the following link:
https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20170419-asa-xauth ["https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20170419-asa-xauth"]</Note>
    <Note Title="Vulnerable Products" Type="General" Ordinal="2">This vulnerability affects Cisco ASA Software running on the following products:

Cisco ASA 1000V Cloud Firewall
Cisco ASA 5500 Series Adaptive Security Appliances
Cisco ASA 5500-X Series Next-Generation Firewalls
Cisco ASA Services Module for Cisco Catalyst 6500 Series Switches and Cisco 7600 Series Routers
Cisco Adaptive Security Virtual Appliance (ASAv)
Cisco ASA for Firepower 9300 Series
Cisco ISA 3000 Industrial Security Appliance
  Refer to the “Fixed Software” section of this security advisory for more information about affected releases.

Cisco ASA Software is affected by this vulnerability if the system is  configured to terminate remote access IKEv1 VPN connections using IPsec client and XAUTH is used for user authentication.

Cisco ASA Software is not affected by this vulnerability if the system  is configured to terminate the following VPN connections:

Clientless SSL
AnyConnect SSL
Internet Key Exchange Version 2 (IKEv2) AnyConnect
LAN-to-LAN VPN
Layer 2 Tunneling Protocol (L2TP)-IPsec VPN
  To determine whether a Cisco ASA Software appliance is configured to terminate IKEv1 remote access VPN  connections, a dynamic crypto map must be configured for at least one  interface. Administrators should use the show running-config crypto map | include interface|dynamic command and verify that the output includes a dynamic crypto map. The following example shows a crypto map named outside_map configured on the outside interface:
ciscoasa# show running-config crypto map | include interface|dynamic
crypto map outside_map 65535 ipsec-isakmp dynamic mydynamic
crypto map outside_map interface outside
    By default, remote access VPN using IPsec VPN clients use XAUTH for user authentication. Administrators can verify whether the VPN client is using XAUTH by using the show running-config all tunnel-group &lt;tg_name&gt; ipsec-attributes | include xauth command and verifying that ikev1 user-authentication xauth is present. The following example shows a Cisco ASA Software appliance with a tunnel-group named RAVPN and with XAUTH configured:
ciscoasa# show  running-config all tunnel-group RAVPN ipsec-attributes | include xauth

[...]
ikev1 user-authentication xauth
  Note: Remote access VPN using an IPsec client is not configured by default; however, when configured, the XAUTH feature will be enabled.

Determining the Running Software Release

To determine whether a vulnerable release of Cisco ASA Software is running on an appliance, administrators can use the show version command. The following example shows the results of the show version command on an appliance running Cisco ASA Software Release 9.2(1):
ciscoasa# show version | include Version
Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance Software Version 9.2(1)   Device Manager Version 7.4(1)
    Customers who use Cisco Adaptive Security Device Manager (ASDM) to manage devices can locate the software release in the table that appears in the login window or the upper-left corner of the Cisco ASDM window.</Note>
    <Note Title="Products Confirmed Not Vulnerable" Type="General" Ordinal="3">No other Cisco products are currently known to be affected by this vulnerability.</Note>
    <Note Title="Workarounds" Type="General" Ordinal="4">There are no workarounds that address this vulnerability</Note>
    <Note Title="Fixed Software" Type="General" Ordinal="5">Cisco has released free software updates that address the vulnerability described in this advisory. Customers may only install and expect support for software versions and feature sets for which they have purchased a license. By installing, downloading, accessing, or otherwise using such software upgrades, customers agree to follow the terms of the Cisco software license:
http://www.cisco.com/en/US/docs/general/warranty/English/EU1KEN_.html ["http://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/td/docs/general/warranty/English/EU1KEN_.html"]

Additionally, customers may only download software for which they have a valid license, procured from Cisco directly, or through a Cisco authorized reseller or partner. In most cases this will be a maintenance upgrade to software that was previously purchased. Free security software updates do not entitle customers to a new software license, additional software feature sets, or major revision upgrades.

When considering software upgrades, customers are advised to regularly consult the advisories for Cisco products, which are available from the Cisco Security Advisories and Alerts page ["https://www.cisco.com/go/psirt"], to determine exposure and a complete upgrade solution.

In all cases, customers should ensure that the devices to be upgraded contain sufficient memory and confirm that current hardware and software configurations will continue to be supported properly by the new release. If the information is not clear, customers are advised to contact the Cisco Technical Assistance Center (TAC) or their contracted maintenance providers.

Customers Without Service Contracts

Customers who purchase directly from Cisco but do not hold a Cisco service contract and customers who make purchases through third-party vendors but are unsuccessful in obtaining fixed software through their point of sale should obtain upgrades by contacting the Cisco TAC:
http://www.cisco.com/en/US/support/tsd_cisco_worldwide_contacts.html ["http://www.cisco.com/en/US/support/tsd_cisco_worldwide_contacts.html"]

Customers should have the product serial number available and be prepared to provide the URL of this advisory as evidence of entitlement to a free upgrade.

Fixed Releases

In the following table, the left column lists major releases of Cisco ASA Software. The right column indicates whether a major release is  affected by the vulnerability described in this advisory and the first release that includes the fix for this vulnerability.

                                    Cisco ASA Software
Major Release                            First Fixed Release                                                Prior to 9.01
              Affected, migrate to 9.1(7.7) or later
                                  9.01
              Affected, migrate to 9.1(7.7) or later
                                  9.1               9.1(7.7) or later
                                  9.2
              9.2(4.11) or later
                                  9.31
              Affected, migrate to 9.4(4) or later
                                  9.4               9.4(4) or later
                                  9.5
              9.5(3) or later
                                  9.6               9.6(1.5) or later
                                  9.7               Not affected
                                  9.8               Not affected

1 Cisco ASA Software releases prior to 9.1 and Cisco ASA Software Release 9.3 have reached end-of-software maintenance. Customers should migrate to a supported release.

Note: It is possible that certain fixed software releases for this vulnerability are affected by a bug described in Cisco Field Notice FN-64291 ["http://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/support/docs/field-notices/642/fn64291.html"] where a security appliance may fail to pass traffic after 213 days of uptime. Customers should review this notice before determining a course of action for addressing the vulnerability described in this advisory. The issue described in the Cisco Field Notice is not a security vulnerability.</Note>
    <Note Title="Vulnerability Policy" Type="General" Ordinal="6">To learn about Cisco security vulnerability disclosure policies and publications, see the Security Vulnerability Policy ["http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html"]. This document also contains instructions for obtaining fixed software and receiving security vulnerability information from Cisco.</Note>
    <Note Title="Exploitation and Public Announcements" Type="General" Ordinal="7">The Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT) is not aware of any public announcements or malicious use of the vulnerability that is described in this advisory.</Note>
    <Note Title="Source" Type="General" Ordinal="8">This vulnerability was found during the resolution of support cases.</Note>
    <Note Title="Legal Disclaimer" Type="Legal Disclaimer" Ordinal="9">THIS DOCUMENT IS PROVIDED ON AN "AS IS" BASIS AND DOES NOT IMPLY ANY KIND OF GUARANTEE OR WARRANTY, INCLUDING THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY OR FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR USE. YOUR USE OF THE INFORMATION ON THE DOCUMENT OR MATERIALS LINKED FROM THE DOCUMENT IS AT YOUR OWN RISK. CISCO RESERVES THE RIGHT TO CHANGE OR UPDATE THIS DOCUMENT AT ANY TIME.

A standalone copy or paraphrase of the text of this document that omits the distribution URL is an uncontrolled copy and may lack important information or contain factual errors. The information in this document is intended for end users of Cisco products.</Note>
  </DocumentNotes>
  <DocumentReferences>
    <Reference Type="Self">
      <URL>https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20170419-asa-xauth</URL>
      <Description>Cisco ASA Software Internet Key Exchange Version 1 XAUTH Denial of Service Vulnerability</Description>
    </Reference>
  </DocumentReferences>
  <ProductTree xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/prod">
    <Branch Name="Cisco" Type="Vendor">
      <Branch Name="Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software" Type="Product Name">
        <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-6588">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software </FullProductName>
      </Branch>
    </Branch>
  </ProductTree>
  <Vulnerability Ordinal="1" xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/vuln">
    <Title>Cisco ASA Software Internet Key Exchange Version 1 XAUTH Denial of Service Vulnerability</Title>
    <ID SystemName="Cisco Bug ID">CSCuz11685</ID>
    <Notes>
      <Note Title="Summary" Type="Summary" Ordinal="1">A vulnerability in the Internet Key Exchange Version 1 (IKEv1) XAUTH code of Cisco ASA Software could allow
an authenticated, remote attacker to cause a reload of an affected
system.



The vulnerability is due to insufficient validation of
the IKEv1 XAUTH parameters passed during an IKEv1 negotiation. An attacker
could exploit this vulnerability by sending crafted parameters.</Note>
      <Note Title="Cisco Bug IDs" Type="Other" Ordinal="2">CSCuz11685</Note>
    </Notes>
    <CVE>CVE-2017-6610</CVE>
    <ProductStatuses>
      <Status Type="Known Affected">
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-6588</ProductID>
      </Status>
    </ProductStatuses>
    <CVSSScoreSets>
      <ScoreSetV3>
        <BaseScoreV3>7.7</BaseScoreV3>
        <VectorV3>CVSS:3.0/AV:N/AC:L/PR:L/UI:N/S:C/C:N/I:N/A:H</VectorV3>
      </ScoreSetV3>
    </CVSSScoreSets>
    <Remediations>
      <Remediation Type="Workaround">
        <Description>There are no workarounds that address this vulnerability</Description>
      </Remediation>
    </Remediations>
    <References>
      <Reference Type="Self">
        <URL>https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20170419-asa-xauth</URL>
        <Description>Cisco ASA Software Internet Key Exchange Version 1 XAUTH Denial of Service Vulnerability</Description>
      </Reference>
    </References>
  </Vulnerability>
</cvrfdoc>