<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cvrfdoc xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/cvrf">
  <DocumentTitle>Cisco WebEx Meetings Server Information Disclosure Vulnerability</DocumentTitle>
  <DocumentType>Cisco Security Advisory</DocumentType>
  <DocumentPublisher Type="Vendor">
    <ContactDetails>Emergency Support:
+1 877 228 7302 (toll-free within North America)
+1 408 525 6532 (International direct-dial)
Non-emergency Support:
Email: psirt@cisco.com
Support requests that are received via e-mail are typically acknowledged within 48 hours.</ContactDetails>
    <IssuingAuthority>Cisco product security incident response is the responsibility of the Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT). The Cisco PSIRT is a dedicated, global team that manages the receipt, investigation, and public reporting of security vulnerability information that is related to Cisco products and networks. The on-call Cisco PSIRT works 24x7 with Cisco customers, independent security researchers, consultants, industry organizations, and other vendors to identify possible security issues with Cisco products and networks.
More information can be found in Cisco Security Vulnerability Policy available at http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html</IssuingAuthority>
  </DocumentPublisher>
  <DocumentTracking>
    <Identification>
      <ID>cisco-sa-20170510-cwms</ID>
    </Identification>
    <Status>Final</Status>
    <Version>1.0</Version>
    <RevisionHistory>
      <Revision>
        <Number>1.0</Number>
        <Date>2017-05-10T15:47:54</Date>
        <Description>Initial public release.</Description>
      </Revision>
    </RevisionHistory>
    <InitialReleaseDate>2017-05-10T16:00:00</InitialReleaseDate>
    <CurrentReleaseDate>2017-05-10T15:47:54</CurrentReleaseDate>
    <Generator>
      <Engine>TVCE</Engine>
    </Generator>
  </DocumentTracking>
  <DocumentNotes>
    <Note Title="Summary" Type="Summary" Ordinal="1">A vulnerability in Cisco WebEx Meetings Server could allow unauthenticated, remote attackers to gain information that could allow them to access scheduled customer meetings.

The vulnerability is due to an incomplete configuration of the robots.txt file on customer-hosted WebEx solutions and occurs when the Short URL functionality is not activated. All releases of Cisco WebEx Meetings Server later than release 2.5MR4 provide this functionality.

An attacker could exploit this vulnerability via an exposed parameter to search for indexed meeting information. A successful exploit could allow the attacker to obtain scheduled meeting information and potentially allow the attacker to attend scheduled, customer meetings.

Cisco has released software updates that address this vulnerability. Workarounds are available to address this vulnerability. This advisory is available at the following link:
https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20170510-cwms ["https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20170510-cwms"]</Note>
    <Note Title="Vulnerable Products" Type="General" Ordinal="2">This vulnerability affects the following releases of Cisco WebEx Meetings Server:

2.5
2.6
2.7
2.8</Note>
    <Note Title="Products Confirmed Not Vulnerable" Type="General" Ordinal="3">No other Cisco products are currently known to be affected by this vulnerability.

Cisco has confirmed that this vulnerability does not affect the following Cisco-hosted WebEx products:

Cisco WebEx Meeting Center
Cisco WebEx Training Center
Cisco WebEx Event Center
Cisco WebEx Support Center
Cisco WebEx Meetings</Note>
    <Note Title="Workarounds" Type="General" Ordinal="4">Customers can enable the Short URL functionality for their individual releases by following the steps in the guide for the appropriate release detailed in the following list. Note: Customers are recommended to configure the block long URL links option below the Short URL function. Once the block long URL links functionality is activated, all previously scheduled meetings become invalid. Customers must reschedule all existing recurring meetings. It is also recommended that customers change their meeting passwords when rescheduling for added security protections.

Guides for Enabling Short URL Functionality

Administration Guide for Release 2.5 ["http://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/td/docs/collaboration/CWMS/2_5/Administration_Guide/Administration_Guide/Administration_Guide_chapter_01111.html#task_E8A47834C9C140ADA3E05809DF253F11"]
Administration Guide for Release 2.6 ["http://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/td/docs/collaboration/CWMS/2_6/Administration_Guide/Administration_Guide/Administration_Guide_chapter_01110.html#task_E8A47834C9C140ADA3E05809DF253F11"]
Administration Guide for Release 2.7 ["http://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/td/docs/collaboration/CWMS/2_7/Administration_Guide/cwms_b_cwms-administration-2-7/cwms_b_cwms-administration-2-7_chapter_01110.html#task_E8A47834C9C140ADA3E05809DF253F11"]
Administration Guide for Release 2.8  ["http://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/td/docs/collaboration/CWMS/2_8/Administration_Guide/cwms_b_cwms-administration-2-8/cwms_b_cwms-administration-2-8test_chapter_01110.html#task_E8A47834C9C140ADA3E05809DF253F11"]</Note>
    <Note Title="Fixed Software" Type="General" Ordinal="5">Cisco has released free software updates that address the vulnerability described in this advisory. Customers may only install and expect support for software versions and feature sets for which they have purchased a license. By installing, downloading, accessing, or otherwise using such software upgrades, customers agree to follow the terms of the Cisco software license:
http://www.cisco.com/en/US/docs/general/warranty/English/EU1KEN_.html ["http://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/td/docs/general/warranty/English/EU1KEN_.html"]

Additionally, customers may only download software for which they have a valid license, procured from Cisco directly, or through a Cisco authorized reseller or partner. In most cases this will be a maintenance upgrade to software that was previously purchased. Free security software updates do not entitle customers to a new software license, additional software feature sets, or major revision upgrades.

When considering software upgrades, customers are advised to regularly consult the advisories for Cisco products, which are available from the Cisco Security Advisories and Alerts page ["https://www.cisco.com/go/psirt"], to determine exposure and a complete upgrade solution.

In all cases, customers should ensure that the devices to be upgraded contain sufficient memory and confirm that current hardware and software configurations will continue to be supported properly by the new release. If the information is not clear, customers are advised to contact the Cisco Technical Assistance Center (TAC) or their contracted maintenance providers.

Customers Without Service Contracts

Customers who purchase directly from Cisco but do not hold a Cisco service contract and customers who make purchases through third-party vendors but are unsuccessful in obtaining fixed software through their point of sale should obtain upgrades by contacting the Cisco TAC:
http://www.cisco.com/en/US/support/tsd_cisco_worldwide_contacts.html ["http://www.cisco.com/en/US/support/tsd_cisco_worldwide_contacts.html"]

Customers should have the product serial number available and be prepared to provide the URL of this advisory as evidence of entitlement to a free upgrade.

Fixed Releases

Cisco WebEx Meetings Server software can be downloaded from the Download Software ["http://www.cisco.com/cisco/software/navigator.html"] site by navigating to  Products &gt; Conferencing &gt; Web Conferencing &gt; WebEx Meetings Server.

                              Cisco WebEx Meetings Server                            First Fixed Release for this Vulnerability                                                2.5              2.5MR6 Patch 6
                                  2.6              2.6MR3 Security Patch 4                                  2.7              2.7MR2 Security Patch 6                                  2.8              2.8 Security Patch 1
Note: After the patch is applied, customers are recommended to enable the block long URL links option, which will invalidate previously scheduled recurring meeting links. Should customers choose to not enable the block long URL links option, previously scheduled meetings will continue to be available for use. Cisco PSIRT recommends that when rescheduling meetings, customers change previously used passwords or utilize a password generator to create new meeting passwords.</Note>
    <Note Title="Vulnerability Policy" Type="General" Ordinal="6">To learn about Cisco security vulnerability disclosure policies and publications, see the Security Vulnerability Policy ["http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html"]. This document also contains instructions for obtaining fixed software and receiving security vulnerability information from Cisco.</Note>
    <Note Title="Exploitation and Public Announcements" Type="General" Ordinal="7">The Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT) is not aware of any public announcements or malicious use of the vulnerability that is described in this advisory.</Note>
    <Note Title="Source" Type="General" Ordinal="8">This vulnerability was reported to Cisco by Mohammed Adel.</Note>
    <Note Title="Legal Disclaimer" Type="Legal Disclaimer" Ordinal="9">THIS DOCUMENT IS PROVIDED ON AN "AS IS" BASIS AND DOES NOT IMPLY ANY KIND OF GUARANTEE OR WARRANTY, INCLUDING THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY OR FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR USE. YOUR USE OF THE INFORMATION ON THE DOCUMENT OR MATERIALS LINKED FROM THE DOCUMENT IS AT YOUR OWN RISK. CISCO RESERVES THE RIGHT TO CHANGE OR UPDATE THIS DOCUMENT AT ANY TIME.

A standalone copy or paraphrase of the text of this document that omits the distribution URL is an uncontrolled copy and may lack important information or contain factual errors. The information in this document is intended for end users of Cisco products.</Note>
  </DocumentNotes>
  <DocumentReferences>
    <Reference Type="Self">
      <URL>https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20170510-cwms</URL>
      <Description>Cisco WebEx Meetings Server Information Disclosure Vulnerability</Description>
    </Reference>
  </DocumentReferences>
  <ProductTree xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/prod">
    <Branch Name="Cisco" Type="Vendor">
      <Branch Name="Cisco WebEx Meetings Server" Type="Product Name">
        <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-190702">Cisco WebEx Meetings Server </FullProductName>
      </Branch>
    </Branch>
  </ProductTree>
  <Vulnerability Ordinal="1" xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/vuln">
    <Title>Cisco WebEx Meetings Server Information Disclosure Vulnerability</Title>
    <ID SystemName="Cisco Bug ID">CSCve25950</ID>
    <Notes>
      <Note Title="Summary" Type="Summary" Ordinal="1">A vulnerability in Cisco WebEx Meetings Server could allow unauthenticated, remote attackers to gain information that could allow them to access scheduled customer meetings.



The vulnerability is due to an incomplete configuration of the robots.txt file on customer-hosted WebEx solutions and occurs when the Short URL functionality is not activated. All releases of Cisco WebEx Meetings Server later than release 2.5MR4 provide this functionality. 



An attacker could exploit this vulnerability via an exposed parameter to search for indexed meeting information. A successful exploit could allow the attacker to obtain scheduled meeting information and potentially allow the attacker to attend scheduled, customer meetings.</Note>
      <Note Title="Cisco Bug IDs" Type="Other" Ordinal="2">CSCve25950</Note>
    </Notes>
    <CVE>CVE-2017-6651</CVE>
    <ProductStatuses>
      <Status Type="Known Affected">
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-190702</ProductID>
      </Status>
    </ProductStatuses>
    <CVSSScoreSets>
      <ScoreSetV3>
        <BaseScoreV3>7.5</BaseScoreV3>
        <VectorV3>CVSS:3.0/AV:N/AC:L/PR:N/UI:N/S:U/C:H/I:N/A:N</VectorV3>
      </ScoreSetV3>
    </CVSSScoreSets>
    <Remediations>
      <Remediation Type="Workaround">
        <Description>Customers can enable the Short URL functionality for their individual releases by following the steps in the guide for the appropriate release detailed in the following list. Note: Customers are recommended to configure the block long URL links option below the Short URL function. Once the block long URL links functionality is activated, all previously scheduled meetings become invalid. Customers must reschedule all existing recurring meetings. It is also recommended that customers change their meeting passwords when rescheduling for added security protections.

Guides for Enabling Short URL Functionality

Administration Guide for Release 2.5 ["http://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/td/docs/collaboration/CWMS/2_5/Administration_Guide/Administration_Guide/Administration_Guide_chapter_01111.html#task_E8A47834C9C140ADA3E05809DF253F11"]
Administration Guide for Release 2.6 ["http://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/td/docs/collaboration/CWMS/2_6/Administration_Guide/Administration_Guide/Administration_Guide_chapter_01110.html#task_E8A47834C9C140ADA3E05809DF253F11"]
Administration Guide for Release 2.7 ["http://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/td/docs/collaboration/CWMS/2_7/Administration_Guide/cwms_b_cwms-administration-2-7/cwms_b_cwms-administration-2-7_chapter_01110.html#task_E8A47834C9C140ADA3E05809DF253F11"]
Administration Guide for Release 2.8  ["http://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/td/docs/collaboration/CWMS/2_8/Administration_Guide/cwms_b_cwms-administration-2-8/cwms_b_cwms-administration-2-8test_chapter_01110.html#task_E8A47834C9C140ADA3E05809DF253F11"]</Description>
      </Remediation>
    </Remediations>
    <References>
      <Reference Type="Self">
        <URL>https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20170510-cwms</URL>
        <Description>Cisco WebEx Meetings Server Information Disclosure Vulnerability</Description>
      </Reference>
    </References>
  </Vulnerability>
</cvrfdoc>