<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cvrfdoc xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/cvrf">
  <DocumentTitle>Cisco Small Business Managed Switches Denial of Service Vulnerability</DocumentTitle>
  <DocumentType>Cisco Security Advisory</DocumentType>
  <DocumentPublisher Type="Vendor">
    <ContactDetails>Emergency Support:
+1 877 228 7302 (toll-free within North America)
+1 408 525 6532 (International direct-dial)
Non-emergency Support:
Email: psirt@cisco.com
Support requests that are received via e-mail are typically acknowledged within 48 hours.</ContactDetails>
    <IssuingAuthority>Cisco product security incident response is the responsibility of the Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT). The Cisco PSIRT is a dedicated, global team that manages the receipt, investigation, and public reporting of security vulnerability information that is related to Cisco products and networks. The on-call Cisco PSIRT works 24x7 with Cisco customers, independent security researchers, consultants, industry organizations, and other vendors to identify possible security issues with Cisco products and networks.
More information can be found in Cisco Security Vulnerability Policy available at http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html</IssuingAuthority>
  </DocumentPublisher>
  <DocumentTracking>
    <Identification>
      <ID>cisco-sa-20170920-sbms</ID>
    </Identification>
    <Status>Final</Status>
    <Version>1.0</Version>
    <RevisionHistory>
      <Revision>
        <Number>1.0</Number>
        <Date>2017-09-20T15:56:50</Date>
        <Description>Initial public release.</Description>
      </Revision>
    </RevisionHistory>
    <InitialReleaseDate>2017-09-20T16:00:00</InitialReleaseDate>
    <CurrentReleaseDate>2017-09-20T15:56:50</CurrentReleaseDate>
    <Generator>
      <Engine>TVCE</Engine>
    </Generator>
  </DocumentTracking>
  <DocumentNotes>
    <Note Title="Summary" Type="Summary" Ordinal="1">A vulnerability in the Secure Shell (SSH) subsystem of Cisco Small Business Managed Switches software could allow an authenticated, remote attacker to cause a reload of the affected switch, resulting in a denial of service (DoS) condition.

The vulnerability is due to improper processing of SSH connections. An attacker could exploit this vulnerability by logging in to an affected switch via SSH and sending a malicious SSH message.

Cisco has released software updates that address this vulnerability. There are no workarounds that address this vulnerability.

This advisory is available at the following link:
https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20170920-sbms ["https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20170920-sbms"]</Note>
    <Note Title="Vulnerable Products" Type="General" Ordinal="2">This vulnerability affects the following Cisco products when SSH is enabled:

Cisco Small Business 300 Series Managed Switches
Cisco Small Business 500 Series Stackable Managed Switches
Cisco 350 Series Managed Switches
Cisco 350X Series Stackable Managed Switches
Cisco 550X Series Stackable Managed Switches
Cisco ESW2 Series Advanced Switches
  Notes:

SSH is not enabled on the affected platforms by default. To verify if SSH is enabled, navigate to Security &gt; TCP/UDP Services and look for the Enabled checkbox next to SSH Service.
This issue is exploitable only with SSH User Authentication by Password enabled under Security &gt; SSH Server &gt; SSH User Authentication. (In 2.x software, this option is visible in Advanced display mode only.)</Note>
    <Note Title="Products Confirmed Not Vulnerable" Type="General" Ordinal="3">No other Cisco products are currently known to be affected by this vulnerability.

Cisco has confirmed that this vulnerability does not affect the following Cisco products:

Cisco Small Business 200 Series Smart Switches
Cisco Small Business 220 Series Smart Plus Switches
Cisco 250 Series Smart Switches</Note>
    <Note Title="Workarounds" Type="General" Ordinal="4">There are no workarounds that address this vulnerability.</Note>
    <Note Title="Fixed Software" Type="General" Ordinal="5">Cisco has released free software updates that address the vulnerability described in this advisory. Customers may only install and expect support for software versions and feature sets for which they have purchased a license. By installing, downloading, accessing, or otherwise using such software upgrades, customers agree to follow the terms of the Cisco software license:
http://www.cisco.com/en/US/docs/general/warranty/English/EU1KEN_.html ["http://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/td/docs/general/warranty/English/EU1KEN_.html"]

Additionally, customers may only download software for which they have a valid license, procured from Cisco directly, or through a Cisco authorized reseller or partner. In most cases this will be a maintenance upgrade to software that was previously purchased. Free security software updates do not entitle customers to a new software license, additional software feature sets, or major revision upgrades.

When considering software upgrades, customers are advised to regularly consult the advisories for Cisco products, which are available from the Cisco Security Advisories and Alerts page ["https://www.cisco.com/go/psirt"], to determine exposure and a complete upgrade solution.

In all cases, customers should ensure that the devices to upgrade contain sufficient memory and confirm that current hardware and software configurations will continue to be supported properly by the new release. If the information is not clear, customers are advised to contact the Cisco Technical Assistance Center (TAC) or their contracted maintenance providers.

Customers Without Service Contracts

Customers who purchase directly from Cisco but do not hold a Cisco service contract and customers who make purchases through third-party vendors but are unsuccessful in obtaining fixed software through their point of sale should obtain upgrades by contacting the Cisco TAC:
http://www.cisco.com/en/US/support/tsd_cisco_worldwide_contacts.html ["http://www.cisco.com/en/US/support/tsd_cisco_worldwide_contacts.html"]

Customers should have the product serial number available and be prepared to provide the URL of this advisory as evidence of entitlement to a free upgrade.

Fixed Releases

                                Cisco Product
              First Fixed Release for This Vulnerability
                                              Small Business 300 Series Managed Switches
              1.4.8.06
                                  Small Business 500 Series Stackable Managed Switches
                                  ESW2 Series Advanced Switches
                                  350 Series Managed Switches
              2.3.0.130

                                  350X Series Stackable Managed Switches
                                  550X Series Stackable Managed Switches

The software can be downloaded from the Software Center ["https://software.cisco.com/download/navigator.html"] on Cisco.com by navigating to Downloads Home &gt; Products &gt; Switches &gt; LAN Switches - Small Business and selecting the respective model.</Note>
    <Note Title="Vulnerability Policy" Type="General" Ordinal="6">To learn about Cisco security vulnerability disclosure policies and publications, see the Security Vulnerability Policy ["http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html"]. This document also contains instructions for obtaining fixed software and receiving security vulnerability information from Cisco.</Note>
    <Note Title="Exploitation and Public Announcements" Type="General" Ordinal="7">The Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT) is not aware of any public announcements or malicious use of the vulnerability that is described in this advisory.</Note>
    <Note Title="Source" Type="General" Ordinal="8">This vulnerability was reported to Cisco by external researcher Alessandro Celestra of TLogos.</Note>
    <Note Title="Legal Disclaimer" Type="Legal Disclaimer" Ordinal="9">THIS DOCUMENT IS PROVIDED ON AN "AS IS" BASIS AND DOES NOT IMPLY ANY KIND OF GUARANTEE OR WARRANTY, INCLUDING THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY OR FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR USE. YOUR USE OF THE INFORMATION ON THE DOCUMENT OR MATERIALS LINKED FROM THE DOCUMENT IS AT YOUR OWN RISK. CISCO RESERVES THE RIGHT TO CHANGE OR UPDATE THIS DOCUMENT AT ANY TIME.

A standalone copy or paraphrase of the text of this document that omits the distribution URL is an uncontrolled copy and may lack important information or contain factual errors. The information in this document is intended for end users of Cisco products.</Note>
  </DocumentNotes>
  <DocumentReferences>
    <Reference Type="Self">
      <URL>https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20170920-sbms</URL>
      <Description>Cisco Small Business Managed Switches Denial of Service Vulnerability</Description>
    </Reference>
  </DocumentReferences>
  <ProductTree xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/prod">
    <Branch Name="Cisco" Type="Vendor">
      <Branch Name="Cisco Small Business 300 Series Managed Switches" Type="Product Name">
        <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-187435">Cisco Small Business 300 Series Managed Switches </FullProductName>
      </Branch>
      <Branch Name="Cisco Small Business 500 Series Stackable Managed Switches" Type="Product Name">
        <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-187436">Cisco Small Business 500 Series Stackable Managed Switches </FullProductName>
      </Branch>
      <Branch Name="Cisco 350 Series Managed Switches" Type="Product Name">
        <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-227821">Cisco 350 Series Managed Switches </FullProductName>
      </Branch>
      <Branch Name="Cisco 350X Series Stackable Managed Switches" Type="Product Name">
        <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-227830">Cisco 350X Series Stackable Managed Switches </FullProductName>
      </Branch>
      <Branch Name="Cisco 550X Series Stackable Managed Switches" Type="Product Name">
        <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-227834">Cisco 550X Series Stackable Managed Switches </FullProductName>
      </Branch>
      <Branch Name="Cisco ESW2 Series Advanced Switches" Type="Product Name">
        <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-227878">Cisco ESW2 Series Advanced Switches </FullProductName>
      </Branch>
    </Branch>
  </ProductTree>
  <Vulnerability Ordinal="1" xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/vuln">
    <Title>Cisco Small Business Managed Switches Denial of Service Vulnerability</Title>
    <ID SystemName="Cisco Bug ID">CSCvb48377</ID>
    <Notes>
      <Note Title="Summary" Type="Summary" Ordinal="1">A vulnerability in the Secure Shell (SSH) subsystem of Cisco Small Business Managed Switches software could allow an authenticated, remote attacker to cause a reload of the affected switch, resulting in a denial of service (DoS) condition.



The vulnerability is due to improper processing of SSH connections. An attacker could exploit this vulnerability by logging in to an affected switch via SSH and sending a malicious SSH message.</Note>
      <Note Title="Cisco Bug IDs" Type="Other" Ordinal="2">CSCvb48377</Note>
    </Notes>
    <CVE>CVE-2017-6720</CVE>
    <ProductStatuses>
      <Status Type="Known Affected">
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-187435</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-187436</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-227821</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-227830</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-227834</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-227878</ProductID>
      </Status>
    </ProductStatuses>
    <CVSSScoreSets>
      <ScoreSetV3>
        <BaseScoreV3>7.7</BaseScoreV3>
        <VectorV3>CVSS:3.0/AV:N/AC:L/PR:L/UI:N/S:C/C:N/I:N/A:H</VectorV3>
      </ScoreSetV3>
    </CVSSScoreSets>
    <Remediations>
      <Remediation Type="Workaround">
        <Description>There are no workarounds that address this vulnerability.</Description>
      </Remediation>
    </Remediations>
    <References>
      <Reference Type="Self">
        <URL>https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20170920-sbms</URL>
        <Description>Cisco Small Business Managed Switches Denial of Service Vulnerability</Description>
      </Reference>
    </References>
  </Vulnerability>
</cvrfdoc>