<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cvrfdoc xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/cvrf">
  <DocumentTitle>Cisco Meeting Server TURN Server Unauthorized Access and Information Disclosure Vulnerability</DocumentTitle>
  <DocumentType>Cisco Security Advisory</DocumentType>
  <DocumentPublisher Type="Vendor">
    <ContactDetails>Emergency Support:
+1 877 228 7302 (toll-free within North America)
+1 408 525 6532 (International direct-dial)
Non-emergency Support:
Email: psirt@cisco.com
Support requests that are received via e-mail are typically acknowledged within 48 hours.</ContactDetails>
    <IssuingAuthority>Cisco product security incident response is the responsibility of the Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT). The Cisco PSIRT is a dedicated, global team that manages the receipt, investigation, and public reporting of security vulnerability information that is related to Cisco products and networks. The on-call Cisco PSIRT works 24x7 with Cisco customers, independent security researchers, consultants, industry organizations, and other vendors to identify possible security issues with Cisco products and networks.
More information can be found in Cisco Security Vulnerability Policy available at http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html</IssuingAuthority>
  </DocumentPublisher>
  <DocumentTracking>
    <Identification>
      <ID>cisco-sa-20170913-cmsturn</ID>
    </Identification>
    <Status>Final</Status>
    <Version>1.0</Version>
    <RevisionHistory>
      <Revision>
        <Number>1.0</Number>
        <Date>2017-09-13T12:50:45</Date>
        <Description>Initial public release.</Description>
      </Revision>
    </RevisionHistory>
    <InitialReleaseDate>2017-09-13T16:00:00</InitialReleaseDate>
    <CurrentReleaseDate>2017-09-13T12:50:45</CurrentReleaseDate>
    <Generator>
      <Engine>TVCE</Engine>
    </Generator>
  </DocumentTracking>
  <DocumentNotes>
    <Note Title="Summary" Type="Summary" Ordinal="1">A vulnerability in the Traversal Using Relay NAT (TURN) server included with Cisco Meeting Server (CMS) could allow an authenticated, remote attacker to gain unauthenticated or unauthorized access to components of or sensitive information in an affected system.

The vulnerability is due to an incorrect default configuration of the TURN server, which could expose internal interfaces and ports on the external interface of an affected system. An attacker could exploit this vulnerability by using a TURN server to perform an unauthorized connection to a Call Bridge, a Web Bridge, or a database cluster in an affected system, depending on the deployment model and CMS services in use. A successful exploit could allow the attacker to gain unauthenticated access to a Call Bridge or database cluster in an affected system or gain unauthorized access to sensitive meeting information in an affected system. To exploit this vulnerability, the attacker must have valid credentials for the TURN server of the affected system.

Cisco has released software updates that address this vulnerability. There are no workarounds that address this vulnerability.

This advisory is available at the following link:
https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20170913-cmsturn ["https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20170913-cmsturn"]</Note>
    <Note Title="Vulnerable Products" Type="General" Ordinal="2">This vulnerability affects Cisco Meeting Server (CMS) deployments that are running a CMS Software release prior to Release 2.0.16, 2.1.11, or 2.2.6, if the deployment meets all the following additional criteria:

The deployment uses the TURN server included with CMS.
The TURN server uses Transport Layer Security (TLS) connections; on the Mainboard Management Processor (MMP) interface, the TLS protocol is configured to run with the TURN server.
The TURN server is running on the same virtual machine as other colocated CMS services.
The TURN server is running on the same virtual machine as a Call Bridge, a Web Bridge, or a database node that is part of a database cluster in the CMS deployment.

Administrators can determine which CMS Software release is running on a device by using the version command in the CLI. The following example shows the output of the command for a device that is running CMS Software Release 2.0.6:


system&gt; version

2_0_6

For TLS to be configured to run with a TURN server, the turn tls and turn certs commands must be present in the configuration. To check the MMP TLS configuration for the TURN server, administrators can issue the turn command in the MMP console.

The following example shows the output of the turn command for a system that does not have TLS configured for the TURN server:


cms&gt; turn
Enabled       : true
Username      : cisco
Password      : 1234
Realm         : nicedet.com
Public IP     : none
Relay address : 1.2.3.4
Listen interface a

The following example shows the output of the turn command for a system that has TLS configured for the TURN server:


cms&gt; turn
Enabled       : true  Username      : cisco  Password      : 1234  Realm         : nicedet.com  Public IP     : none  Relay address : 1.2.3.4  TLS port               : 3479  TLS cert               : turn.crt  TLS key       : turn.key  TLS bundle    : none  Listen interface a</Note>
    <Note Title="Products Confirmed Not Vulnerable" Type="General" Ordinal="3">No other Cisco products are currently known to be affected by this vulnerability.

Cisco has confirmed that this vulnerability does not affect CMS deployments that meet any of the following conditions:

The deployment does not use a TURN server.
The deployment uses a third-party TURN server.
The TURN server is running on a dedicated CMS with no other colocated services.
The TLS configuration is disabled for the TURN server.</Note>
    <Note Title="Details" Type="General" Ordinal="4">Cisco Meeting Server (CMS) incorporates video, audio, and content-sharing capabilities into software that can be accessed via a conference room, desktop, or mobile device. CMS works across Cisco video rooms and connects with Skype for Business and other hardware providers to allow a seamless meeting architecture. This capability exists via collaboration between Cisco and Acano, who joined Cisco in early 2016.

  The TURN server included with CMS contains a vulnerability that could allow an authenticated, remote attacker to gain unauthorized access to components of or sensitive information in an affected system, depending on the deployment model and CMS services in use. The vulnerability is due to an incorrect default configuration of the TURN server, which could expose internal interfaces and ports on the external interface of an affected system.

If the TURN server is running on the same virtual machine (colocated) as a CMS Call Bridge, the attacker could gain unauthenticated access to the Web Admin interface of CMS Software.

If the TURN server is colocated with a CMS Web Bridge, the attacker could receive lookup messages for meeting conferences, which may contain call identifiers and passcodes for meetings.

If the TURN server is colocated with a database node that is part of a CMS database cluster, an attacker could gain unauthenticated access to the database for that cluster.

To exploit this vulnerability, the attacker must have valid credentials for and authenticate to the TURN server of the affected system.

For additional information about configuring CMS TURN servers, refer to the “TURN Server” section of the Cisco Meeting Server Scalability &amp; Resilience Server Deployment Guide ["https://www.cisco.com/c/dam/en/us/td/docs/conferencing/ciscoMeetingServer/Deployment_Guide/Version-2-1/Cisco-Meeting-Server-2-1-Scalable-and-Resilient-Deployments.pdf"].</Note>
    <Note Title="Workarounds" Type="General" Ordinal="5">There are no workarounds that address this vulnerability.</Note>
    <Note Title="Fixed Software" Type="General" Ordinal="6">Cisco has released free software updates that address the vulnerability described in this advisory. Customers may only install and expect support for software versions and feature sets for which they have purchased a license. By installing, downloading, accessing, or otherwise using such software upgrades, customers agree to follow the terms of the Cisco software license:  https://www.cisco.com/en/US/docs/general/warranty/English/EU1KEN_.html ["https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/td/docs/general/warranty/English/EU1KEN_.html"]

Additionally, customers may only download software for which they have a valid license, procured from Cisco directly, or through a Cisco authorized reseller or partner. In most cases this will be a maintenance upgrade to software that was previously purchased. Free security software updates do not entitle customers to a new software license, additional software feature sets, or major revision upgrades.

When considering software upgrades, customers are advised to regularly consult the advisories for Cisco products, which are available from the Cisco Security Advisories and Alerts page ["https://www.cisco.com/go/psirt"], to determine exposure and a complete upgrade solution.

In all cases, customers should ensure that the devices to be upgraded contain sufficient memory and confirm that current hardware and software configurations will continue to be supported properly by the new release. If the information is not clear, customers are advised to contact the Cisco Technical Assistance Center (TAC) or their contracted maintenance providers.

Customers Without Service Contracts

Customers who purchase directly from Cisco but do not hold a Cisco service contract and customers who make purchases through third-party vendors but are unsuccessful in obtaining fixed software through their point of sale should obtain upgrades by contacting the Cisco TAC: https://www.cisco.com/en/US/support/tsd_cisco_worldwide_contacts.html ["https://www.cisco.com/en/US/support/tsd_cisco_worldwide_contacts.html"]

Customers should have the product serial number available and be prepared to provide the URL of this advisory as evidence of entitlement to a free upgrade.

Fixed Releases

This vulnerability is fixed in CMS Software Releases 2.0.16, 2.1.11, 2.2.6, and later. Customers should upgrade to the latest software release by visiting the Software Center ["https://software.cisco.com/download/navigator.html"] on Cisco.com and navigating to Products &gt; Conferencing &gt; Video Conferencing &gt; Multiparty Conferencing &gt; Meeting Server.

For information about the CMS software release model, refer to Cisco Meeting Server: End of maintenance and support policy ["https://www.cisco.com/c/dam/en/us/td/docs/conferencing/ciscoMeetingServer/White_papers/Cisco-Meeting-Server-End-of-Maintenance-and-support-of-sofware.pdf"].</Note>
    <Note Title="Vulnerability Policy" Type="General" Ordinal="7">To learn about Cisco security vulnerability disclosure policies and publications, see the Security Vulnerability Policy ["http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html"]. This document also contains instructions for obtaining fixed software and receiving security vulnerability information from Cisco.</Note>
    <Note Title="Exploitation and Public Announcements" Type="General" Ordinal="8">The Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT) is not aware of any public announcements or malicious use of the vulnerability that is described in this advisory.</Note>
    <Note Title="Source" Type="General" Ordinal="9">This vulnerability was found during internal security testing.</Note>
    <Note Title="Legal Disclaimer" Type="Legal Disclaimer" Ordinal="10">THIS DOCUMENT IS PROVIDED ON AN "AS IS" BASIS AND DOES NOT IMPLY ANY KIND OF GUARANTEE OR WARRANTY, INCLUDING THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY OR FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR USE. YOUR USE OF THE INFORMATION ON THE DOCUMENT OR MATERIALS LINKED FROM THE DOCUMENT IS AT YOUR OWN RISK. CISCO RESERVES THE RIGHT TO CHANGE OR UPDATE THIS DOCUMENT AT ANY TIME.

A standalone copy or paraphrase of the text of this document that omits the distribution URL is an uncontrolled copy and may lack important information or contain factual errors. The information in this document is intended for end users of Cisco products.</Note>
  </DocumentNotes>
  <DocumentReferences>
    <Reference Type="Self">
      <URL>https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20170913-cmsturn</URL>
      <Description>Cisco Meeting Server TURN Server Unauthorized Access and Information Disclosure Vulnerability</Description>
    </Reference>
  </DocumentReferences>
  <ProductTree xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/prod">
    <Branch Name="Cisco" Type="Vendor">
      <Branch Name="Cisco Meeting Server" Type="Product Name">
        <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-217166">Cisco Meeting Server </FullProductName>
      </Branch>
    </Branch>
  </ProductTree>
  <Vulnerability Ordinal="1" xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/vuln">
    <Title>Cisco Meeting Server TURN Server Unauthorized Access and Information Disclosure Vulnerability</Title>
    <ID SystemName="Cisco Bug ID">CSCvf51127</ID>
    <Notes>
      <Note Title="Summary" Type="Summary" Ordinal="1">A vulnerability in the Traversal Using Relay NAT (TURN) server included with Cisco Meeting Server (CMS) could allow an authenticated, remote attacker to gain unauthenticated or unauthorized access to components of or sensitive information in an affected system.



The vulnerability is due to an incorrect default configuration of the TURN server, which could expose internal interfaces and ports on the external interface of an affected system. An attacker could exploit this vulnerability by using a TURN server to perform an unauthorized connection to a Call Bridge, a Web Bridge, or a database cluster in an affected system, depending on the deployment model and CMS services in use. A successful exploit could allow the attacker to gain unauthenticated access to a Call Bridge or database cluster in an affected system or gain unauthorized access to sensitive meeting information in an affected system. To exploit this vulnerability, the attacker must have valid credentials for the TURN server of the affected system.</Note>
      <Note Title="Cisco Bug IDs" Type="Other" Ordinal="2">CSCvf51127</Note>
    </Notes>
    <CVE>CVE-2017-12249</CVE>
    <ProductStatuses>
      <Status Type="Known Affected">
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-217166</ProductID>
      </Status>
    </ProductStatuses>
    <CVSSScoreSets>
      <ScoreSetV3>
        <BaseScoreV3>9.1</BaseScoreV3>
        <VectorV3>CVSS:3.0/AV:N/AC:L/PR:H/UI:N/S:C/C:H/I:H/A:H</VectorV3>
      </ScoreSetV3>
    </CVSSScoreSets>
    <Remediations>
      <Remediation Type="Workaround">
        <Description>There are no workarounds that address this vulnerability.</Description>
      </Remediation>
    </Remediations>
    <References>
      <Reference Type="Self">
        <URL>https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20170913-cmsturn</URL>
        <Description>Cisco Meeting Server TURN Server Unauthorized Access and Information Disclosure Vulnerability</Description>
      </Reference>
    </References>
  </Vulnerability>
</cvrfdoc>