<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cvrfdoc xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.icasi.org/CVRF/schema/cvrf/1.1">
  <DocumentTitle>Cisco IOS SSL VPN Vulnerability</DocumentTitle>
  <DocumentType>Cisco Security Advisory</DocumentType>
  <DocumentPublisher Type="Vendor">
    <ContactDetails>Emergency Support:
+1 877 228 7302 (toll-free within North America)
+1 408 525 6532 (International direct-dial)
Non-emergency Support:
Email: psirt@cisco.com
Support requests that are received via e-mail are typically acknowledged within 48 hours.</ContactDetails>
    <IssuingAuthority>Cisco product security incident response is the responsibility of the Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT). The Cisco PSIRT is a dedicated, global team that manages the receipt, investigation, and public reporting of security vulnerability information that is related to Cisco products and networks. The on-call Cisco PSIRT works 24x7 with Cisco customers, independent security researchers, consultants, industry organizations, and other vendors to identify possible security issues with Cisco products and networks.
More information can be found in Cisco Security Vulnerability Policy available at http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html</IssuingAuthority>
  </DocumentPublisher>
  <DocumentTracking>
    <Identification>
      <ID>cisco-sa-20100922-sslvpn</ID>
    </Identification>
    <Status>Final</Status>
    <Version>1.1</Version>
    <RevisionHistory>
      <Revision>
        <Number>1.1</Number>
        <Date>2010-09-22T16:00:00</Date>
        <Description>No Description Available</Description>
      </Revision>
    </RevisionHistory>
    <InitialReleaseDate>2010-09-22T16:00:00</InitialReleaseDate>
    <CurrentReleaseDate>2010-09-22T16:00:00</CurrentReleaseDate>
    <Generator>
      <Engine>TVCE</Engine>
    </Generator>
  </DocumentTracking>
  <DocumentNotes>
    <Note Title="Summary" Type="General" Ordinal="1">Cisco IOS® Software contains a vulnerability when the Cisco IOS SSL VPN
feature is configured with an HTTP redirect. Exploitation could allow a remote,
unauthenticated user to cause a memory leak on the affected devices, that could
result in a memory exhaustion condition that may cause device reloads, the
inability to service new TCP connections, and other denial of service (DoS)
conditions.

Cisco has released software updates that address this vulnerability. There is a workaround to mitigate this vulnerability.

This advisory is posted at
http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20100922-sslvpn["http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20100922-sslvpn"].



Note: The September 22, 2010, Cisco IOS Software Security Advisory bundled
publication includes six Cisco Security Advisories. Five of the advisories
address vulnerabilities in Cisco IOS Software, and one advisory addresses
vulnerabilities in Cisco Unified Communications Manager. Each advisory lists
the releases that correct the vulnerability or vulnerabilities detailed in the
advisory. The table at the following URL lists releases that correct all Cisco
IOS Software vulnerabilities that have been published on September 22, 2010, or
earlier: 


http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20100922-bundle["http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20100922-bundle"]


 Individual publication links are in "Cisco Event Response:
Semiannual Cisco IOS Software Security Advisory Bundled Publication" at the
following link: 


http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/intelligence/Cisco_ERP_sep10.html["http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/intelligence/Cisco_ERP_sep10.html"]

</Note>
  </DocumentNotes>
  <DocumentReferences>
    <Reference Type="Self">
      <URL>http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20100922-sslvpn</URL>
      <Description>Cisco IOS SSL VPN Vulnerability</Description>
    </Reference>
    <Reference>
      <URL>http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityBundle/cisco-sa-20100922-bundle</URL>
      <Description>Summary of Cisco IOS Software Bundled Advisories, September 22, 2010</Description>
    </Reference>
    <Reference>
      <URL>http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityBundle/cisco-sa-20100922-bundle</URL>
      <Description>Summary of Cisco IOS Software Bundled Advisories, September 22, 2010</Description>
    </Reference>
  </DocumentReferences>
  <ProductTree xmlns="http://www.icasi.org/CVRF/schema/prod/1.1">
    <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-106499">Cisco IOS 15.0(1)M</FullProductName>
    <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-99645">Cisco IOS 15.0(1)M1</FullProductName>
    <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-107433">Cisco IOS 15.1(1)T</FullProductName>
  </ProductTree>
  <Vulnerability Ordinal="1" xmlns="http://www.icasi.org/CVRF/schema/vuln/1.1">
    <Title>Cisco IOS Software Secure Sockets Layer Virtual Private Network Denial of Service Vulnerability</Title>
    <ID SystemName="Cisco Bug ID">CSCtg21685</ID>
    <Notes>
      <Note Title="Cisco Bug IDs" Type="Other" Ordinal="2">CSCtg21685</Note>
    </Notes>
    <CVE>CVE-2010-2836</CVE>
    <ProductStatuses>
      <Status Type="Known Affected">
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-99645</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-106499</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-107433</ProductID>
      </Status>
    </ProductStatuses>
    <CVSSScoreSets>
      <ScoreSet>
        <BaseScore>7.8</BaseScore>
        <TemporalScore>6.4</TemporalScore>
        <Vector>AV:N/AC:L/Au:N/C:N/I:N/A:C/E:F/RL:OF/RC:C/CDP:N/TD:N/CR:ND/IR:ND/AR:ND</Vector>
      </ScoreSet>
    </CVSSScoreSets>
    <Remediations>
      <Remediation Type="Workaround">
        <Description>Disabling HTTP redirection for SSL VPN connections can be used as a
workaround for this vulnerability. HTTP redirection for SSL VPN connections is
disabled by executing the command no http-redirect
port in webvpn gateway configuration
mode. 

In addition, manually clearing the hung TCBs with the command
clear tcp tcb * will transition the TCBs into a CLOSED state.
After a time they will clear the CLOSED state and the memory will be
released.


Note:  Clearing the TCB will clear both legitimate and hung connections,
including remote connections to the device such as Telnet and SSH
connections.

The Cisco Applied Mitigation Bulletin (AMB) "Identifying and Mitigating
Exploitation of the TCP State Manipulation Denial of Service Vulnerabilities in
Multiple Cisco Products", available at
http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoAppliedMitigationBulletin/cisco-amb-20090908-tcp24["http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoAppliedMitigationBulletin/cisco-amb-20090908-tcp24"],
contains two mitigations (EEM scripts and SNMP) that can be used to detect and
clear hung TCP connections.

Embedded Event Manager (EEM)
A Cisco IOS Embedded Event Manager (EEM) policy that is based on Tool
Command Language (Tcl) can be used on vulnerable Cisco IOS devices to identify
and detect a hung, extended, or indefinite TCP connection that is caused by
this vulnerability. The policy allows administrators to monitor TCP connections
on a Cisco IOS device. When Cisco IOS EEM detects potential exploitation of
this vulnerability, the policy can trigger a response by sending a syslog
message or a Simple Network Management Protocol (SNMP) trap to clear the TCP
connection. The example policy provided in this document is based on a Tcl
script that monitors and parses the output from two commands at defined
intervals, produces a syslog message when the monitor threshold reaches its
configured value, and can reset the TCP connection.

The Tcl script is available for download at the "Cisco Beyond: Embedded
Event Manager (EEM) Scripting Community" at the following link:
http://forums.cisco.com/eforum/servlet/EEM?page=eem&amp;fn=script&amp;scriptId=2041["http://forums.cisco.com/eforum/servlet/EEM?page=eem&amp;fn=script&amp;scriptId=2041"].
A sample device configuration is provided below.


    
!
    !-- Location where the Tcl script will be stored
    !


    event manager directory user policy disk0:/eem

    
!
    !-- Define variable and set the monitoring interval
    !-- as an integer (expressed in seconds)
    !


    event manager environment EEM_MONITOR_INTERVAL 60

    
!
    !-- Define variable and set the threshold value as
    !-- an integer for the number of retransmissions
    !-- that determine if the TCP connection is hung
    !-- (a recommended value to use is 15)
    !


    event manager environment EEM_MONITOR_THRESHOLD 15

    
!
    !-- Define variable and set the value to "yes" to
    !-- enable the clearing of hung TCP connections
    !


    event manager environment EEM_MONITOR_CLEAR yes

    
!
    !-- Define variable and set to the TCP connection
    !-- state or states that script will monitor, which
    !-- can be a single state or a space-separated list
    !-- of states
    !


    event manager environment EEM_MONITOR_STATES CLOSEWAIT

    
!
    !-- Register the script as a Cisco EEM policy
    !


    event manager policy monitor-sockets.tcl

    !

For more details, refer to the sections "EEM Detecting And Clearing
Hung TCP Connection" and "Identification: Detecting and Clearing Hung TCP
Connection Using SNMP" of this AMB at the following link:
http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoAppliedMitigationBulletin/cisco-amb-20090908-tcp24["http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoAppliedMitigationBulletin/cisco-amb-20090908-tcp24"].
</Description>
      </Remediation>
    </Remediations>
    <References>
      <Reference Type="Self">
        <URL>http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20100922-sslvpn</URL>
        <Description>Cisco IOS SSL VPN Vulnerability</Description>
      </Reference>
    </References>
  </Vulnerability>
</cvrfdoc>