<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cvrfdoc xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/cvrf">
  <DocumentTitle>Cisco ASA Software IKEv1 and IKEv2 Buffer Overflow Vulnerability</DocumentTitle>
  <DocumentType>Cisco Security Advisory</DocumentType>
  <DocumentPublisher Type="Vendor">
    <ContactDetails>Emergency Support:
+1 877 228 7302 (toll-free within North America)
+1 408 525 6532 (International direct-dial)
Non-emergency Support:
Email: psirt@cisco.com
Support requests that are received via e-mail are typically acknowledged within 48 hours.</ContactDetails>
    <IssuingAuthority>Cisco product security incident response is the responsibility of the Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT). The Cisco PSIRT is a dedicated, global team that manages the receipt, investigation, and public reporting of security vulnerability information that is related to Cisco products and networks. The on-call Cisco PSIRT works 24x7 with Cisco customers, independent security researchers, consultants, industry organizations, and other vendors to identify possible security issues with Cisco products and networks.
More information can be found in Cisco Security Vulnerability Policy available at http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html</IssuingAuthority>
  </DocumentPublisher>
  <DocumentTracking>
    <Identification>
      <ID>cisco-sa-20160210-asa-ike</ID>
    </Identification>
    <Status>Final</Status>
    <Version>1.3</Version>
    <RevisionHistory>
      <Revision>
        <Number>1.0</Number>
        <Date>2016-02-10T14:51:03</Date>
        <Description>Initial public release.</Description>
      </Revision>
      <Revision>
        <Number>1.1</Number>
        <Date>2016-02-12T14:48:58</Date>
        <Description>Updated Indicators of Compromise and Exploitation and Public Announcements with additional information.</Description>
      </Revision>
      <Revision>
        <Number>1.2</Number>
        <Date>2016-02-16T23:06:30</Date>
        <Description>Updated information in Vulnerable Products and Fixed Software section. Added additional signatures to Indicators of Compromise.</Description>
      </Revision>
      <Revision>
        <Number>1.3</Number>
        <Date>2016-05-18T13:50:25</Date>
        <Description>Added information about availability of public exploit.</Description>
      </Revision>
    </RevisionHistory>
    <InitialReleaseDate>2016-02-10T16:00:00</InitialReleaseDate>
    <CurrentReleaseDate>2016-05-18T13:50:25</CurrentReleaseDate>
    <Generator>
      <Engine>TVCE</Engine>
    </Generator>
  </DocumentTracking>
  <DocumentNotes>
    <Note Title="Summary" Type="Summary" Ordinal="1">A vulnerability in the Internet Key Exchange (IKE) version 1 (v1)
and IKE version 2 (v2) code of Cisco ASA Software could allow an unauthenticated,
remote attacker to cause a reload of the affected system or to remotely
execute code. 



The vulnerability is due to a buffer overflow in
the affected code area. An attacker could exploit this vulnerability by
sending crafted UDP packets to the affected system. An exploit
could allow the attacker to execute arbitrary code and obtain full
control of the system or to cause a reload of the affected system.



Note: Only traffic directed to the affected system can
be used to exploit this vulnerability. This vulnerability affects
systems configured in routed firewall mode only and in single or
multiple context mode. This vulnerability can be triggered by IPv4 and
IPv6 traffic.



Cisco has released software updates that address this vulnerability.
This advisory is available at the following link:

http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20160210-asa-ike["http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20160210-asa-ike"]</Note>
    <Note Title="Affected Products" Type="General" Ordinal="2">Affected Cisco ASA Software running on the following products may be affected by this vulnerability:


    Cisco ASA 5500 Series Adaptive Security Appliances
    Cisco ASA 5500-X Series Next-Generation Firewalls
    Cisco ASA Services Module for Cisco Catalyst 6500 Series Switches and Cisco 7600 Series Routers
    Cisco ASA 1000V Cloud Firewall 
    Cisco Adaptive Security Virtual Appliance (ASAv) 
    Cisco Firepower 9300 ASA Security Module
    Cisco ISA 3000 Industrial Security Appliance



Refer to the "Fixed Software" section of this security advisory for more information about the affected releases.</Note>
    <Note Title="Vulnerable Products" Type="General" Ordinal="3">Cisco ASA Software is affected by this vulnerability if the system is configured to terminate IKEv1 or IKEv2 VPN connections or if configured as an Easy VPN hardware client.



Cisco ASA Software configured to terminate IKEv1 or IKEv2 VPN Connections



Cisco ASA Software is affected by this vulnerability if the system is configured to terminate IKEv1 or IKEv2 VPN connections. This includes the following:


    LAN-to-LAN IPsec VPN
    Remote access VPN using the IPsec VPN client
    Layer 2 Tunneling Protocol (L2TP)-over-IPsec VPN connections
    IKEv2 AnyConnect 

Cisco ASA Software is not affected by this vulnerability if the system is configured to terminate only the following VPN connections:


    Clientless SSL 
    AnyConnect SSL

To determine whether the Cisco ASA is configured to terminate IKEv1 or IKEv2 VPN
connections, a crypto map must be configured for at least one
interface. Administrators should use the show running-config crypto map | include interface command and verify that it returns output. The following example shows a crypto map called outside_map configured on the outside interface:


ciscoasa# show running-config crypto map | include interface
crypto map outside_map interface outside
Note: Due to a misconfiguration or to a partial configuration, the IKEv1 or IKEv2 process may still accept incoming IKE messages even if a crypto map is not configured. Administrators who do not have a crypto map configured should also check that IKEv1 or IKEv2 is disabled on the affected system. 



To verify that IKEv1 is enabled, use the following commands and verify that the command returns output:


    show running-config crypto ikev1 | include enable command for Cisco ASA Software releases 8.4 and later
    show running-config crypto isakmp | include enable command for Cisco ASA Software releases between 7.2.1 and 8.4
    show running-config | include isakmp enable command for Cisco ASA Software releases prior to 7.2.1 

To verify that IKEv2 is enabled, use the show running-config crypto ikev2 | include enable and verify that it returns output.



Cisco ASA Software Configured as Easy VPN Hardware Client



Cisco ASA Software is affected by this vulnerability if the system is configured as an Easy VPN hardware client.



To verify that the system is configured as Easy VPN hardware client, use the show running-config vpnclient | include enable and verify that it returns output. The following example shows Cisco ASA configured as an Easy VPN hardware client:




ciscoasa# show running-config vpnclient | include enable
vpnclient enable 


Note: To exploit this vulnerability on Cisco ASA Software configured as an Easy VPN hardware client, an attacker must force the Cisco ASA to connect to a malicious VPN server.




</Note>
    <Note Title="Products Confirmed Not Vulnerable" Type="General" Ordinal="4">No other Cisco products are currently known to be affected by this vulnerability.</Note>
    <Note Title="Indicators of Compromise" Type="General" Ordinal="5">Cisco IPS Signatures 7169-0 and 7169-1 and Snort SIDs 36903 and 37674 can detect attempts to exploit this vulnerability.</Note>
    <Note Title="Workarounds" Type="General" Ordinal="6">There are no workarounds that address this vulnerability.</Note>
    <Note Title="Fixed Software" Type="General" Ordinal="7">Cisco has released free software updates that address the vulnerability described in this advisory. Customers may only install and expect support for software versions and feature sets for which they have purchased a license. By installing, downloading, accessing, or otherwise using such software upgrades, customers agree to follow the terms of the Cisco software license:

http://www.cisco.com/en/US/docs/general/warranty/English/EU1KEN_.html

["http://www.cisco.com/en/US/docs/general/warranty/English/EU1KEN_.html"]

Additionally, customers may only download software for which they have a valid license, procured from Cisco directly, or through a Cisco authorized reseller or partner. In most cases this will be a maintenance upgrade to software that was previously purchased. Free security software updates do not entitle customers to a new software license, additional software feature sets, or major revision upgrades.



When considering software upgrades, customers are advised to consult the Cisco Security Advisories and Responses archive at http://www.cisco.com/go/psirt["http://www.cisco.com/go/psirt"] and review subsequent advisories to determine exposure and a complete upgrade solution.



In all cases, customers should ensure that the devices to upgrade contain sufficient memory and confirm that current hardware and software configurations will continue to be supported properly by the new release. If the information is not clear, customers are advised to contact the Cisco Technical Assistance Center (TAC) or their contracted maintenance providers.



Customers Without Service Contracts



Customers who purchase directly from Cisco but do not hold a Cisco service contract and customers who make purchases through third-party vendors but are unsuccessful in obtaining fixed software through their point of sale should obtain upgrades by contacting the Cisco Technical Assistance Center (TAC):

http://www.cisco.com/en/US/support/tsd_cisco_worldwide_contacts.html["http://www.cisco.com/en/US/support/tsd_cisco_worldwide_contacts.html"]



Customers should have the product serial number available and be prepared to provide the URL of this advisory as evidence of entitlement to a free upgrade.



Fixed Releases



In the following table, the left column lists major releases of Cisco
ASA Software. The right column indicates whether a major release is
affected by the vulnerability described in this advisory and the first release that includes the fix for this vulnerability.




    
        
            Cisco ASA Major Release 
            
            First Fixed Release 
            
        
        
            7.21 

            
            Affected; migrate to 9.1(6.11) or later 
        
        
            8.01

            
            Affected; migrate to 9.1(6.11) or later 

            
        
        
            8.11 

            
            Affected; migrate to 9.1(6.11) or later 

            
        
        
            8.21

            
            8.2(5.59)2

            
        
        
            8.31 

            
            Affected; migrate to 9.1(6.11) or later

            
        
        
            8.4 
            8.4(7.30) or later

            
        
        
            8.51 

            
            Not affected

            
        
        
            8.61 

            
            Affected; migrate to 9.1(6.11) or later 
        
        
            8.7 
            8.7(1.18) or later

            
        
        
            9.0 

            
            9.0(4.38) or later

            
        
        
            9.1 
            9.1(6.11) or later

            
        
        
            9.2 
            9.2(4.5) or later

            
        
        
            9.3 
            9.3(3.7) or later

            
        
        
            9.4 
            9.4(2.4) or later

            
        
        
            9.5 

            
            9.5(2.2) or later

            
        
    



1Cisco ASA Software releases 7.2, 8.0, 8.1, 8.2, 8.3, 8.5, and 8.6 have reached End of Software Maintenance. Customers should migrate to a supported release.

2Cisco ASA Software release 8.2 reached End of Software Maintenance on October 21, 2015. To protect our customers still using the End of Support train 8.2 software, the Cisco ASA product team has made available an off-cycle release to address this issue. As Cisco has no plans for additional off-cycle updates to train 8.2, we recommend customers work with their relevant support organization to migrate to supported software.




Software Download




Cisco ASA Software can be downloaded from the Software Center on Cisco.com by visiting http://www.cisco.com/cisco/software/navigator.html["http://www.cisco.com/cisco/software/navigator.html"].



For Cisco ASA 5500 Series Adaptive Security Appliances and Cisco ASA
5500-X Series Next-Generation Firewall, navigate to the following path. To find
interim versions, click All Releases &gt; Interim on the left side of the download page.

Products &gt; Security &gt; Firewalls &gt; Adaptive
Security Appliances (ASA) &gt; ASA 5500-X Series Firewalls &gt;  &gt; Software on Chassis &gt; Adaptive Security
Appliance (ASA) Software

For the Cisco ASA Services Module for Cisco Catalyst 6500 Series
Switches and Cisco 7600 Series Routers, navigate to the following path.
To find interim versions, click All Releases &gt; Interim on the left side of the download page.

Products &gt; Cisco Interfaces and Modules
&gt; Services Modules &gt; Catalyst 6500 Series / 7600 Series ASA
Services Module &gt; Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software

For the Cisco ASA 1000V Cloud Firewall, navigate to the following path:

Products &gt; Security &gt; Firewalls &gt; Adaptive Security Appliances (ASA) &gt; ASA 1000V Cloud Firewall

For the Cisco Adaptive Security Virtual Appliance (ASAv), navigate to the following path:

Products &gt; Security &gt; Firewalls &gt;
Adaptive Security Appliances (ASA) &gt; Adaptive Security Virtual
Appliance (ASAv) &gt; Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software

For the Cisco Firepower 9300 ASA Module, navigate to the following path:

Products &gt; Security &gt; Firewalls &gt; Next-Generation Firewalls (NGFW) &gt; Firepower 9000 Series &gt; Firepower 9300
Security Appliance &gt;Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software

For the Cisco ISA 3000 Industrial Security Appliance, navigate to the following path:


Products &gt; Security &gt; Firewalls &gt; 3000 Series Industrial Security Appliances (ISA) &gt;   &gt; Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software</Note>
    <Note Title="Vulnerability Policy" Type="General" Ordinal="8">To learn about Cisco security vulnerability disclosure policies and publications, see the Security Vulnerability Policy["http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html"]. This document also contains instructions for obtaining fixed software and receiving security vulnerability information from Cisco.
</Note>
    <Note Title="Exploitation and Public Announcements" Type="General" Ordinal="9">The Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT) is not aware of any malicious use of the vulnerability that is described in this advisory.




Exodus Intelligence has provided a public blog post at the following location:

https://blog.exodusintel.com/2016/02/10/firewall-hacking/



On May 17, 2016, Exodus Intelligence also posted a proof-of-concept script at the following location:

https://github.com/exodusintel/disclosures/blob/master/CVE_2016_1287_PoC
</Note>
    <Note Title="Source" Type="General" Ordinal="10">This vulnerability was reported to Cisco by David Barksdale, Jordan Gruskovnjak, and Alex Wheeler of Exodus
Intelligence.</Note>
    <Note Title="Legal Disclaimer" Type="Legal Disclaimer" Ordinal="11">THIS DOCUMENT IS PROVIDED ON AN "AS IS" BASIS AND DOES NOT IMPLY ANY KIND OF GUARANTEE OR WARRANTY, INCLUDING THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY OR FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR USE. YOUR USE OF THE INFORMATION ON THE DOCUMENT OR MATERIALS LINKED FROM THE DOCUMENT IS AT YOUR OWN RISK. CISCO RESERVES THE RIGHT TO CHANGE OR UPDATE THIS DOCUMENT AT ANY TIME.

A standalone copy or paraphrase of the text of this document that omits the distribution URL is an uncontrolled copy and may lack important information or contain factual errors. The information in this document is intended for end users of Cisco products.
</Note>
  </DocumentNotes>
  <DocumentReferences>
    <Reference Type="Self">
      <URL>http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20160210-asa-ike</URL>
      <Description>Cisco ASA Software IKEv1 and IKEv2 Buffer Overflow Vulnerability</Description>
    </Reference>
  </DocumentReferences>
  <ProductTree xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/prod">
    <Branch Name="Cisco" Type="Vendor">
      <Branch Name="Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software" Type="Product Name">
        <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-6588">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software </FullProductName>
      </Branch>
    </Branch>
  </ProductTree>
  <Vulnerability Ordinal="1" xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/vuln">
    <Title>Cisco ASA IKEv1 and IKEv2 Buffer Overflow Vulnerability</Title>
    <ID SystemName="Cisco Bug ID">CSCux42019</ID>
    <Notes>
      <Note Title="Summary" Type="Summary" Ordinal="1">A vulnerability in the Internet Key Exchange (IKE) version 1 (v1)
and IKE version 2 (v2) code of Cisco ASA Software could allow an unauthenticated,
remote attacker to cause a reload of the affected system or to remotely
execute code. 



The vulnerability is due to a buffer overflow in
the affected code area. An attacker could exploit this vulnerability by
sending crafted UDP packets to the affected system. An exploit
could allow the attacker to execute arbitrary code and obtain full
control of the system or to cause a reload of the affected system.



Note: Only traffic directed to the affected system can
be used to exploit this vulnerability. This vulnerability affects
systems configured in routed firewall mode only and in single or
multiple context mode. This vulnerability can be triggered by IPv4 and
IPv6 traffic.</Note>
      <Note Title="Cisco Bug IDs" Type="Other" Ordinal="2">CSCux42019,CSCux29978</Note>
    </Notes>
    <CVE>CVE-2016-1287</CVE>
    <ProductStatuses>
      <Status Type="Known Affected">
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-6588</ProductID>
      </Status>
    </ProductStatuses>
    <CVSSScoreSets>
      <ScoreSetV2>
        <BaseScoreV2>10.0</BaseScoreV2>
        <TemporalScoreV2>8.3</TemporalScoreV2>
        <VectorV2>AV:N/AC:L/Au:N/C:C/I:C/A:C/E:F/RL:OF/RC:C</VectorV2>
      </ScoreSetV2>
    </CVSSScoreSets>
    <Remediations>
      <Remediation Type="Workaround">
        <Description>There are no workarounds that address this vulnerability.</Description>
      </Remediation>
    </Remediations>
    <References>
      <Reference Type="Self">
        <URL>http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20160210-asa-ike</URL>
        <Description>Cisco ASA Software IKEv1 and IKEv2 Buffer Overflow Vulnerability</Description>
      </Reference>
    </References>
  </Vulnerability>
</cvrfdoc>