<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cvrfdoc xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/cvrf">
  <DocumentTitle>Cisco NX-OS Software TCP Netstack Denial of Service Vulnerability</DocumentTitle>
  <DocumentType>Cisco Security Advisory</DocumentType>
  <DocumentPublisher Type="Vendor">
    <ContactDetails>Emergency Support:
+1 877 228 7302 (toll-free within North America)
+1 408 525 6532 (International direct-dial)
Non-emergency Support:
Email: psirt@cisco.com
Support requests that are received via e-mail are typically acknowledged within 48 hours.</ContactDetails>
    <IssuingAuthority>Cisco product security incident response is the responsibility of the Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT). The Cisco PSIRT is a dedicated, global team that manages the receipt, investigation, and public reporting of security vulnerability information that is related to Cisco products and networks. The on-call Cisco PSIRT works 24x7 with Cisco customers, independent security researchers, consultants, industry organizations, and other vendors to identify possible security issues with Cisco products and networks.
More information can be found in Cisco Security Vulnerability Policy available at http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html</IssuingAuthority>
  </DocumentPublisher>
  <DocumentTracking>
    <Identification>
      <ID>cisco-sa-20160302-netstack</ID>
    </Identification>
    <Status>Final</Status>
    <Version>1.4</Version>
    <RevisionHistory>
      <Revision>
        <Number>1.0</Number>
        <Date>2016-03-02T15:35:33</Date>
        <Description>Initial public release.</Description>
      </Revision>
      <Revision>
        <Number>1.1</Number>
        <Date>2016-03-03T14:43:52</Date>
        <Description>Updated the first fixed release for Nexus 3000 Series Switches.</Description>
      </Revision>
      <Revision>
        <Number>1.3</Number>
        <Date>2017-11-28T20:53:30</Date>
        <Description>Metadata update.</Description>
      </Revision>
      <Revision>
        <Number>1.4</Number>
        <Date>2017-12-05T19:23:56</Date>
        <Description>Metadata update.</Description>
      </Revision>
    </RevisionHistory>
    <InitialReleaseDate>2016-03-02T16:00:00</InitialReleaseDate>
    <CurrentReleaseDate>2017-12-05T19:23:56</CurrentReleaseDate>
    <Generator>
      <Engine>TVCE</Engine>
    </Generator>
  </DocumentTracking>
  <DocumentNotes>
    <Note Title="Summary" Type="Summary" Ordinal="1">4A vulnerability in the TCP stack of Cisco NX-OS Software could allow an unauthenticated, remote attacker to cause a denial of service (DoS) condition.

The vulnerability is due to improper processing of certain TCP packets in the closing sequence of a TCP session while the affected device is in a TIME_WAIT state. An attacker could exploit this vulnerability by sending a specific TCP packet to an affected device on a TCP session that is already in a TIME_WAIT state. An exploit could allow the attacker to cause a reload of the TCP stack on the affected device, resulting in a DoS condition.

This vulnerability can be exploited using either IPv4 or IPv6 packets. The vulnerability can be triggered by a crafted sequence of TCP packets destined for TCP ports listening on the device. The packets may use the IPv4 or IPv6 unicast address of any interface configured on the device.

This vulnerability can be triggered only by traffic destined to an affected device and cannot be exploited using traffic that transits an affected device.

Cisco has released software updates that address this vulnerability. There are no workarounds that address this vulnerability.

This advisory is available at the following link:
http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20160302-netstack ["http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20160302-netstack"]</Note>
    <Note Title="Affected Products" Type="General" Ordinal="2" />
    <Note Title="Vulnerable Products" Type="General" Ordinal="3">This vulnerability affects the following products:

      Cisco Nexus 1000V Series Switches
      Cisco Nexus 3000 Series Switches
      Cisco Nexus 4000 Series Switches
      Cisco Nexus 5000  Series Switches
      Cisco Nexus 6000 Series Switches
      Cisco Nexus 7000 Series Switches
      Cisco Unified Computing System (UCS) running Cisco NX-OS Software
  To determine whether a device is running a vulnerable release of Cisco NX-OS Software, administrators can use the show version command in the NX-OS command-line interface (CLI).

The following example shows the output of this command for a Cisco Nexus 5000 Series Switch running Cisco NX-OS Software Release 7.1(1)N1(1):
# show version
Cisco Nexus Operating System (NX-OS) Software  TAC support: http://www.cisco.com/tac  Documents: http://www.cisco.com/en/US/products/ps9372/tsd_products_support_series_home.html  Copyright (c) 2002-2012, Cisco Systems, Inc. All rights reserved.  The copyrights to certain works contained herein are owned by  other third parties and are used and distributed under license.  Some parts of this software are covered under the GNU Public  License. A copy of the license is available at  http://www.gnu.org/licenses/gpl.html.    Software  BIOS:      version 3.6.0  loader:    version N/A  kickstart: version 7.1(1)N1(1)  system:    version 7.1(1)N1(1)</Note>
    <Note Title="Products Confirmed Not Vulnerable" Type="General" Ordinal="4">No other Cisco products are currently known to be affected by this vulnerability.

Cisco has confirmed that this vulnerability does not affect Cisco Multilayer Director Switches.</Note>
    <Note Title="Indicators of Compromise" Type="General" Ordinal="5">Exploitation of this vulnerability will cause an affected device to reload and generate a netstack core file. Contact the Cisco Technical Assistance Center (TAC) to review the core file and determine whether the device has been compromised by exploitation of this vulnerability.</Note>
    <Note Title="Workarounds" Type="General" Ordinal="6">There are no workarounds that address this vulnerability.</Note>
    <Note Title="Fixed Software" Type="General" Ordinal="7">Cisco has released free software updates that address the vulnerability described in this advisory. Customers may only install and expect support for software versions and feature sets for which they have purchased a license. By installing, downloading, accessing, or otherwise using such software upgrades, customers agree to follow the terms of the Cisco software license: http://www.cisco.com/en/US/docs/general/warranty/English/EU1KEN_.html ["http://www.cisco.com/en/US/docs/general/warranty/English/EU1KEN_.html"]

Additionally, customers may only download software for which they have a valid license, procured from Cisco directly, or through a Cisco authorized reseller or partner. In most cases this will be a maintenance upgrade to software that was previously purchased. Free security software updates do not entitle customers to a new software license, additional software feature sets, or major revision upgrades.

When considering software upgrades, customers are advised to consult the Cisco Security Advisories and Responses archive at http://www.cisco.com/go/psirt ["http://www.cisco.com/go/psirt"] and review subsequent advisories to determine exposure and a complete upgrade solution.

In all cases, customers should ensure that the devices to upgrade contain sufficient memory and confirm that current hardware and software configurations will continue to be supported properly by the new release. If the information is not clear, customers are advised to contact the Cisco Technical Assistance Center (TAC) or their contracted maintenance providers.

  Customers Without Service Contracts

Customers who purchase directly from Cisco but do not hold a Cisco service contract and customers who make purchases through third-party vendors but are unsuccessful in obtaining fixed software through their point of sale should obtain upgrades by contacting the Cisco Technical Assistance Center (TAC): http://www.cisco.com/en/US/support/tsd_cisco_worldwide_contacts.html ["http://www.cisco.com/en/US/support/tsd_cisco_worldwide_contacts.html"]

Customers should have the product serial number available and be prepared to provide the URL of this advisory as evidence of entitlement to a free upgrade.

Fixed Releases

Customers should upgrade to an appropriate release as indicated in the applicable table in this section. To help ensure a complete upgrade solution, consider that this advisory is part of a collection that includes the following advisories:
cisco-sa-20160302-n5ksnmp ["http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20160302-n5ksnmp"]: Cisco NX-OS Software SNMP Packet Denial of Service Vulnerability
cisco-sa-20160302-netstack ["http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20160302-netstack"]: Cisco NX-OS Software TCP Netstack Denial of Service Vulnerability
cisco-sa-20160302-n3k ["http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20160302-n3k"]: Cisco Nexus 3000 Series and 3500 Platform Switches Insecure Default Credentials Vulnerability
  In the following table, the left column lists major releases of Cisco NX-OS Software. The center column indicates whether a major release is affected by the vulnerability described in this advisory and the first minor release that includes the fix for this vulnerability. The right column indicates whether a major release is affected by all the vulnerabilities described in this collection of advisories and which release includes fixes for those vulnerabilities.

                              Cisco NX-OS Software Major Release - Cisco UCS
              First Fixed Release for This Vulnerability              First Fixed Release for This Vulnerability and All Vulnerabilities Described in the Collection of Advisories
                                  Prior to 2.1               Affected; migrate to 2.2(2c)
              2.2(2c) or later                                   2.1
              Affected; migrate to 2.2(2c)
              2.2(2c) or later

                                  2.2
              2.2(2c)              2.2(2c) or later                                  3.0               Not affected              Not affected

                              Cisco NX-OS Software Major Release - Nexus 1000V Series Switches
              First Fixed Release for This Vulnerability              First Fixed Release for This Vulnerability and All Vulnerabilities Described in the Collection of Advisories
                                  Prior to 5.2              Affected; migrate to 5.2(1)SV3(1.1)              5.2(1)SV3(1.1) or later
                                  5.2              5.2(1)SV3(1.1)
              5.2(1)SV3(1.1) or later

                              Cisco NX-OS Software Major Release - Nexus 3000 Series Switches
              First Fixed Release for This Vulnerability              First Fixed Release for This Vulnerability and All Vulnerabilities Described in the Collection of Advisories
                                  Prior to 6.0              Affected; migrate to 6.0(2)U1(1)
              6.0(2)U6(5a) or later                                  6.0              6.0(2)U1(1)
              6.0(2)U6(5a) or later
                                  7.0              Not affected              Not affected

                              Cisco NX-OS Software Major Release - Nexus 3500 Platform Switches
              First Fixed Release for This Vulnerability              First Fixed Release for This Vulnerability and All Vulnerabilities Described in the Collection of Advisories
                                  Prior to 6.0              Affected; migrate to 6.0(2)A1(1)
              6.0(2)A6(5a) or later                                  6.0              6.0(2)A1(1)
              6.0(2)A6(5a) or later
                                  7.0              Not affected              Not affected

                              Cisco NX-OS Software Major Release - Nexus 4000 Series Switches
              First Fixed Release for This Vulnerability              First Fixed Release for This Vulnerability and All Vulnerabilities Described in the Collection of Advisories
                                  4.1              4.1(2)E1(1n)
              4.1(2)E1(1n) or later
                              Cisco NX-OS Software
Major Release - Nexus 5000 Series Switches
              First Fixed Release for This Vulnerability              First Fixed Release for This Vulnerability and All Vulnerabilities Described in the Collection of Advisories                                   Prior to 5.2               Affected; migrate to 5.2(1)N1(9)               5.2(1)N1(9) or later
                                  5.2
              5.2(1)N1(9)
              5.2(1)N1(9)or later

                              Cisco NX-OS Software
Major Release - Nexus 5500 Platform and 6000 Series Switches
              First Fixed Release for This Vulnerability              First Fixed Release for This Vulnerability and All Vulnerabilities Described in the Collection of Advisories                                   Prior to 5.2               Affected; migrate to 5.2(1)N1(9)               7.1(2)N1(1) or later
                                  5.2
              5.2(1)N1(9)
              5.2(1)N1(9) or later
                                  6.0
              6.0(2)N2(7)
              6.0(2)N2(7) or later
                                  7.0               7.0(0)N1(1)               7.0(0)N1(1) or later
                                  7.1               Not affected               7.1(2)N1(1) or later
                                  7.2               Not affected               7.1(2)N1(1) or later

                              Cisco NX-OS Software Major Release - Nexus 7000 Series and 7700 Series Switches
              First Fixed Release for This Vulnerability              First Fixed Release for This Vulnerability and All Vulnerabilities Described in the Collection of Advisories
                                  Prior to 5.2              Affected; migrate to 5.2(9)
              5.2(9) or later                                  5.2
              5.2(9)
              5.2(9) or later
                                  6.0              Affected; migrate to 6.1(4a)              6.1(4a) or later
                                  6.1               6.1(4a)               6.1(4a) or later
                                  6.2               6.2(2)              6.2(2) or later
                                  7.2               Not affected              Not affected                                  7.3              Not affected
              Not affected


Release Recommendations

For additional assistance in determining the best NX-OS Software release for a Cisco Nexus Switch, refer to the recommended release document for the switch:

Cisco Nexus 1000V for VMware Switches ["http://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/td/docs/switches/datacenter/nexus1000/sw/recommended_releases/b_Cisco_N1KV_VMware_MinRecommendedReleases.html"]
Cisco Nexus 3000 Series and 3500 Series Switches ["http://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/td/docs/switches/datacenter/nexus3000/sw/recommended_release/b_Minimum_and_Recommended_Cisco_NX-OS_Releases_for_Cisco_Nexus_3000_Series_Switches.html"]
Cisco Nexus 5000 Series Switches ["http://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/td/docs/switches/datacenter/nexus5000/sw/release/recommended_releases/recommended_nx-os_releases.html"]
Cisco Nexus 5500 Platform Switches ["http://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/td/docs/switches/datacenter/nexus5500/sw/release/recommended_releases/n5500_recommended_nx-os_releases.html"]
Cisco Nexus 6000 Series Switches ["http://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/td/docs/switches/datacenter/nexus6000/sw/release/recommended_releases/recommended_nx-os_releases.html"]
Cisco Nexus 7000 Series Switches ["http://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/td/docs/switches/datacenter/sw/nx-os/recommended_releases/recommended_nx-os_releases.html"]
  To determine the best NX-OS software release for Cisco UCS or a Cisco Nexus 4000 Series Switch, refer to the Recommended Releases documents in the release notes for the device.</Note>
    <Note Title="Vulnerability Policy" Type="General" Ordinal="8">To learn about Cisco security vulnerability disclosure policies and publications, see the Security Vulnerability Policy ["http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html"]. This document also contains instructions for obtaining fixed software and receiving security vulnerability information from Cisco.</Note>
    <Note Title="Exploitation and Public Announcements" Type="General" Ordinal="9">The Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT) is not aware of any public announcements or malicious use of the vulnerability that is described in this advisory.</Note>
    <Note Title="Source" Type="General" Ordinal="10">This vulnerability was found during the resolution of a support case.</Note>
    <Note Title="Legal Disclaimer" Type="Legal Disclaimer" Ordinal="11">THIS DOCUMENT IS PROVIDED ON AN "AS IS" BASIS AND DOES NOT IMPLY ANY KIND OF GUARANTEE OR WARRANTY, INCLUDING THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY OR FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR USE. YOUR USE OF THE INFORMATION ON THE DOCUMENT OR MATERIALS LINKED FROM THE DOCUMENT IS AT YOUR OWN RISK. CISCO RESERVES THE RIGHT TO CHANGE OR UPDATE THIS DOCUMENT AT ANY TIME.

A standalone copy or paraphrase of the text of this document that omits the distribution URL is an uncontrolled copy and may lack important information or contain factual errors. The information in this document is intended for end users of Cisco products.</Note>
  </DocumentNotes>
  <DocumentReferences>
    <Reference Type="Self">
      <URL>http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20160302-netstack</URL>
      <Description>Cisco NX-OS Software TCP Netstack Denial of Service Vulnerability</Description>
    </Reference>
  </DocumentReferences>
  <ProductTree xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/prod">
    <Branch Name="Cisco" Type="Vendor">
      <Branch Name="Cisco NX-OS Software" Type="Product Name">
        <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-80720">Cisco NX-OS Software </FullProductName>
      </Branch>
      <Branch Name="Cisco Unified Computing System (Managed)" Type="Product Name">
        <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-112776">Cisco Unified Computing System (Managed) </FullProductName>
      </Branch>
    </Branch>
  </ProductTree>
  <Vulnerability Ordinal="1" xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/vuln">
    <Title>Cisco NX-OS Software TCP Netstack Denial of Service Vulnerability</Title>
    <ID SystemName="Cisco Bug ID">CSCub70579</ID>
    <Notes>
      <Note Title="Summary" Type="Summary" Ordinal="1">A vulnerability in the TCP stack of Cisco NX-OS Software could allow an unauthenticated, remote attacker to cause a denial of service (DoS) condition.



The vulnerability is due to improper processing of certain TCP packets in the closing sequence of a TCP session while the affected device is in a TIME_WAIT state. An attacker could exploit this vulnerability by sending a specific TCP packet to an affected device on a TCP session that is already in a TIME_WAIT state. An exploit could allow the attacker to cause a reload of the TCP stack on the affected device, resulting in a DoS condition.</Note>
      <Note Title="Cisco Bug IDs" Type="Other" Ordinal="2">CSCub70579,CSCue79544,CSCup97337,CSCup97366,CSCuo58749,CSCup97345</Note>
    </Notes>
    <CVE>CVE-2015-0718</CVE>
    <ProductStatuses>
      <Status Type="Known Affected">
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-80720</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-112776</ProductID>
      </Status>
    </ProductStatuses>
    <CVSSScoreSets>
      <ScoreSetV2>
        <BaseScoreV2>7.8</BaseScoreV2>
        <TemporalScoreV2>6.4</TemporalScoreV2>
        <VectorV2>AV:N/AC:L/Au:N/C:N/I:N/A:C/E:F/RL:OF/RC:C</VectorV2>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-80720</ProductID>
      </ScoreSetV2>
    </CVSSScoreSets>
    <Remediations>
      <Remediation Type="Workaround">
        <Description>There are no workarounds that address this vulnerability.</Description>
      </Remediation>
    </Remediations>
    <References>
      <Reference Type="Self">
        <URL>http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20160302-netstack</URL>
        <Description>Cisco NX-OS Software TCP Netstack Denial of Service Vulnerability</Description>
      </Reference>
    </References>
  </Vulnerability>
</cvrfdoc>